
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – CNCF</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/cncf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CNCF on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Jimmy Song</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Jimmy Song</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:11:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/cncf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
                                                         
    
                                                   
                           
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon EU 2024 Transparency Report Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/kubecon-eu-2024-transparency-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:11:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/kubecon-eu-2024-transparency-report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Recently, the CNCF released the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/reports/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe-2024/&#34; title=&#34;KubeCon EU 2024 Transparency Report&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KubeCon EU 2024 Transparency Report&lt;/a&gt;. The KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Europe 2024 held in Paris was the largest event in its history, and I had the fortune to attend in person. The beauty of Paris and the atmosphere of the conference were unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/kubecon-eu-2024-transparency-report/report-cover_hu2b5f4d718cbd8af635ae5d9a18644567_36245_500x705_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/kubecon-eu-2024-transparency-report/report-cover.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/kubecon-eu-2024-transparency-report/report-cover.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;500&#34; data-height=&#34;705&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;KubeCon &amp;#43; CloudNativeCon EU 2024 Transparency Report Cover&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;KubeCon + CloudNativeCon EU 2024 Transparency Report Cover&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We witnessed the power of the open-source and cloud-native communities and how they drive the next major technological shift — artificial intelligence. At this conference, CNCF announced the establishment of an AI working group and launched the first edition of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/blog/cloud-native-ai-whitepaper/&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native AI Whitepaper&#34;&gt;Cloud Native AI Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;, followed by the creation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rx-m.github.io/cnai-landscape/?group=cnai&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native AI Landscape&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Native AI Landscape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://rx-m.github.io/cnai-landscape/embed/embed.html?key=cnai&amp;headers=true&amp;category-header=true&amp;category-in-subcategory=false&amp;item-name=false&amp;title-uppercase=false&amp;title-alignment=left&amp;title-font-family=sans-serif&amp;title-font-size=13&amp;style=shadowed&amp;size=xs&amp;items-alignment=left&amp;bg-color=%23016bcc&amp;fg-color=%23ffffff&amp;base-path=%2Fcnai-landscape&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:500px;display:block;border:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;growth-and-diversity&#34;&gt;Growth and Diversity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event welcomed over 12,000 participants, with the majority (78%) coming from Europe and 52% attending for the first time. Participants from different regions showed enthusiasm for cloud-native technologies. The diverse functional backgrounds of the participants, including business operations, developers, and architects, highlighted the wide application of cloud-native technology across fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table shows the top 10 countries by attendee numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Number of Attendees&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,956&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,879&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,733&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;816&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;797&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Switzerland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;368&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;355&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Israel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;312&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Poland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;303&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;293&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovation-and-communication&#34;&gt;Innovation and Communication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the event, there were 331 sessions and 19 keynote speeches covering hot topics such as artificial intelligence, application development, and platform engineering. This edition of KubeCon also hosted poster sessions and project tours for researchers, helping attendees better understand various projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-and-inclusivity&#34;&gt;Community and Inclusivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeCon is committed to supporting diversity, equity, and inclusion. Activities such as diversity lunches and Peer Group Mentoring provided platforms for participants to connect and support each other. (PS. The catering at the venue was not to my liking, especially the taste of the tea and the hard bread.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;environmental-and-sustainability&#34;&gt;Environmental and Sustainability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of environmental and sustainability efforts, the organizers chose venues with an environmental consciousness and implemented measures to reduce food waste and recycle waste, demonstrating CNCF&amp;rsquo;s commitment to environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-forward&#34;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, we hope to bring the magic of KubeCon to more regions globally. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the upcoming KubeCon + CloudNativeCon China 2024 or other regional events, I am very much looking forward to meeting you. I have also submitted a panel session for KubeCon China, and if selected, we will meet in Hong Kong this August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Europe 2024 was not just a technical gathering, but a display of community strength. If you would like to know more details, please check out my previous recap of &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/kubecon-eu-paris-recap/&#34; title=&#34;KubeCon &amp;#43; CloudNativeCon Europe&#34;&gt;KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Europe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this transparency report helps you better understand the impact of the event and inspires you to participate in future KubeCon events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>In-depth Analysis of CNCF&#39;s Cloud Native AI Whitepaper</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/cloud-native-ai-whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:54:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/cloud-native-ai-whitepaper/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In March 2024, during KubeCon EU, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) released its first detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/reports/cloud-native-artificial-intelligence-whitepaper/&#34; title=&#34;whitepaper&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; on Cloud Native Artificial Intelligence (CNAI). This report thoroughly explores the current state, challenges, and future directions of integrating Cloud Native technologies with artificial intelligence. This article delves into the core content of this whitepaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-cloud-native-ai&#34;&gt;What is Cloud Native AI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native AI refers to the approach of building and deploying artificial intelligence applications and workloads using Cloud Native technology principles. This includes leveraging microservices, containerization, declarative APIs, and continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) to enhance the scalability, reusability, and operability of AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below illustrates the architecture of Cloud Native AI, redrawn based on the whitepaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/cloud-native-ai-whitepaper/cloud-native-ai.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/cloud-native-ai-whitepaper/cloud-native-ai.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cloud Native AI Architecture&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cloud Native AI Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relationship-between-cloud-native-ai-and-cloud-native-technologies&#34;&gt;Relationship Between Cloud Native AI and Cloud Native Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native technologies provide a flexible, scalable platform that makes the development and operation of AI applications more efficient. Through containerization and microservices architecture, developers can iterate and deploy AI models rapidly while ensuring high availability and scalability of systems. Kubernetes and other Cloud Native tools provide essential support such as resource scheduling, automatic scaling, and service discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whitepaper provides two examples illustrating the relationship between Cloud Native AI and Cloud Native technologies, namely running AI on Cloud Native infrastructure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/blog/hugging-face-endpoints-on-azure&#34; title=&#34;Hugging Face Collaborates with Microsoft to launch Hugging Face Model Catalog on Azure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugging Face Collaborates with Microsoft to launch Hugging Face Model Catalog on Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/research/scaling-kubernetes-to-7500-nodes&#34; title=&#34;OpenAI Scaling Kubernetes to 7,500 nodes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OpenAI Scaling Kubernetes to 7,500 nodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges-of-cloud-native-ai&#34;&gt;Challenges of Cloud Native AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite providing a solid foundation for AI applications, Cloud Native technologies still face challenges when integrating AI workloads with Cloud Native platforms. These challenges include the complexity of data preparation, resource requirements for model training, and maintaining the security and isolation of models in multi-tenant environments. Additionally, resource management and scheduling in Cloud Native environments are crucial, especially for large-scale AI applications, and further optimization is needed to support efficient model training and inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-path-of-cloud-native-ai&#34;&gt;Development Path of Cloud Native AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whitepaper proposes several development paths for Cloud Native AI, including improving resource scheduling algorithms to better support AI workloads, developing new service mesh technologies to enhance the performance and security of AI applications, and driving innovation and standardization of Cloud Native AI technology through open-source projects and community collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-native-ai-technology-landscape&#34;&gt;Cloud Native AI Technology Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native AI involves a variety of technologies, from containers and microservices to service meshes and serverless computing. Kubernetes is a key platform for deploying and managing AI applications, while service mesh technologies like Istio and Envoy provide powerful traffic management and security features. Additionally, monitoring tools like Prometheus and Grafana are essential for maintaining the performance and reliability of AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the Cloud Native AI landscape provided in the whitepaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-orchestration&#34;&gt;General Orchestration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volcano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Armada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kuberay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nvidia NeMo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunikorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kueue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;distributed-training&#34;&gt;Distributed Training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubeflow Training Operator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pytorch DDP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TensorFlow Distributed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open MPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepSpeed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Megatron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horovod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ml-serving&#34;&gt;ML Serving&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kserve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seldon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLLM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TGT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skypilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cicd---delivery&#34;&gt;CI/CD - Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubeflow Pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mlflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BentoML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MLRun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science&#34;&gt;Data Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubeflow Notebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyTorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Zeppelin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;workload-observability&#34;&gt;Workload Observability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Influxdb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weights and Biases (wandb)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenTelemetry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;automl&#34;&gt;AutoML&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperopt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optuna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubeflow Katib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NNI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance--policy&#34;&gt;Governance &amp;amp; Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kyverno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kyverno-JSON&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OPA/Gatekeeper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StackRox Minder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-architecture&#34;&gt;Data Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ClickHouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Pinot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Druid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassandra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ScyllaDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop HDFS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache HBase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Flink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulsar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memcached&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alluxio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Superset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vector-databases&#34;&gt;Vector Databases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milvus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chroma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weaviate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quadrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinecone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensions
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postgres SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ElasticSearch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modelllm-observability&#34;&gt;Model/LLM Observability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trulens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Langfuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deepchecks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenLLMetry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, let me summarizes the following key points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role of the Open Source Community&lt;/strong&gt;: The whitepaper clearly points out the role of the open-source community in advancing Cloud Native AI, including accelerating innovation and reducing costs through open-source projects and extensive collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance of Cloud Native Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;: Cloud Native AI is built and deployed according to Cloud Native principles, highlighting the importance of repeatability and scalability. Cloud Native technologies provide an efficient development and runtime environment for AI applications, especially in terms of resource scheduling and service scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges Exist&lt;/strong&gt;: Despite the many advantages brought by Cloud Native AI, there are still challenges in data preparation, model training resource requirements, and model security and isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Development Directions&lt;/strong&gt;: The whitepaper proposes development paths including optimizing resource scheduling algorithms to support AI workloads, developing new service mesh technologies to enhance performance and security, and leveraging open-source projects and community collaboration to further promote technological innovation and standardization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Technological Components&lt;/strong&gt;: Key technologies involved in Cloud Native AI include containers, microservices, service meshes, and serverless computing. Kubernetes plays a central role in deploying and managing AI applications, while service mesh technologies such as Istio and Envoy provide necessary traffic management and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, please download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/reports/cloud-native-artificial-intelligence-whitepaper/&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native AI Whitepaper&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Native AI Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>ICA Certification: Latest Changes and Exam Preparation Guide for Istio Skills</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-certificate/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-and-reminders-for-ica-certification&#34;&gt;Changes and Reminders for ICA Certification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming policy change: Please note that the ICA certification expiration policy will change on April 1, 2024, at 00:00UTC. Certifications obtained on or after this date will expire 24 months after meeting the certification requirements (including passing the exam). We encourage anyone interested and prepared to schedule and take the exam before the policy change. Please see more detailed information &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com&#34; title=&#34;here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current certification validity period is 3 years, and certifications obtained after April 1st will be valid for 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-on-tetrate-academy&#34;&gt;Background on Tetrate Academy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academy.tetrate.io/&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate Academy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate Academy&lt;/a&gt;, operated by Tetrate, has been around for several years, launching Istio fundamentals tutorials, Envoy fundamentals tutorials, and CIAT certification exams, with over 13,000 people having taken Tetrate Academy courses. In September last year, Tetrate contributed CIAT to CNCF, renamed it &lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;ICA exam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ICA exam&lt;/a&gt;, and the certification exam was officially launched in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;domains.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34;
         alt=&#34;ICA domains by Linux Foundation&#34;data-img=&#34;domains.jpg&#34;
         data-caption=&#34;&#34;
         
         
         data-width=&#34;1000&#34;
         data-height=&#34;968&#34;
         
         
    /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;ICA domains by &lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;Linux Foundation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exam-background&#34;&gt;Exam Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICA is derived from the CIAT exam contributed by Tetrate, providing validation of extensive knowledge and skills in Istio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam is conducted remotely online, with a time limit of 2 hours, during which candidates need to operate Kubernetes clusters and Istio in a virtual machine environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam includes a series of problem-solving questions and some multiple-choice questions, requiring a passing score of 75%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PSI system provides an online exam environment, and exam results will be emailed to candidates within 24 hours after the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam environment provides tools such as Kubernetes clusters, Istio installation, VS Code, kubectl, istioctl, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to Istio documentation is available during the exam, and questions and responses are in English only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations-and-reminders&#34;&gt;Recommendations and Reminders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io&#34; title=&#34;Istio documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio documentation&lt;/a&gt; before the exam, and prepare in advance, including checking the PSI system, identification, and exam environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s free &lt;a href=&#34;https://academy.tetrate.io/courses/istio-fundamentals&#34; title=&#34;Istio fundamentals tutorial&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio fundamentals tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to deepen your understanding of Istio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay calm during the exam, answer familiar questions first, then unfamiliar ones, to ensure efficient completion of the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-links&#34;&gt;Reference Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.linuxfoundation.org/tc-docs/certification/frequently-asked-questions-ica&#34; title=&#34;ICA Certification FAQs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ICA Certification FAQs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.linuxfoundation.org/tc-docs/certification/important-instructions-ica&#34; title=&#34;Important Instructions for ICA Certification&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Important Instructions for ICA Certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>A Month in Review: The Impact of Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification with Tetrate&#39;s Contribution</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cloud computing professionals, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month since the &lt;strong&gt;Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification&lt;/strong&gt; journey began. A collaboration between the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), Linux Foundation Training &amp;amp; Certification, and Tetrate, this certification has set a new benchmark in microservices management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tetrate.io&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate&lt;/a&gt;, a key contributor to the Istio project, initially crafted the Certified Istio Administrator by Tetrate (CIAT), which laid the groundwork for the ICA Certification. Since its introduction, the ICA has been an instrumental part of the Kubernetes ecosystem, helping thousands to harness the power of service mesh technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certification curriculum covers essential domains such as &lt;strong&gt;installation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;traffic management&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;, reflecting the comprehensive expertise needed in the field. In a short span, the ICA has gained significant momentum, underpinned by the vision and dedication of Tetrate to the cloud-native landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we celebrate one month of the ICA, Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s commitment to open source education continues through their Tetrate Academy, providing free, high-quality courses on service mesh and Kubernetes security. For those aiming to deploy Istio in production, Tetrate offers the &lt;strong&gt;Tetrate Istio Distribution (TID)&lt;/strong&gt;, a secure and supported Istio distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, now is the time to join this growing community of Istio experts. Enhance your career and contribute to the evolution of cloud-native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-ica-certification-todayhttpstraininglinuxfoundationorgcertificationistio-certified-associate-ica&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning. Let&amp;rsquo;s look forward to more milestones in service mesh proficiency, with Tetrate and CNCF leading the charge.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native With Me - The Past, Current and Future</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/cloud-native-and-me-the-past-current-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:37:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/cloud-native-and-me-the-past-current-and-future/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Today I am honored to announce that I have become a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/people/ambassadors/&#34; title=&#34;CNCF Ambassador&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNCF Ambassador&lt;/a&gt;. Here is my story with Cloud Native.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time to attend the Cloud Native Computing Foundation is at the LC3 in Beijing 2017. I attended the meeting again this year, and in November of this year, CNCF will hold the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lfasiallc.com/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-china-2018/&#34; title=&#34;KubeCon &amp;amp;amp; CloudNativeCon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon&lt;/a&gt; for the first time in Shanghai, China. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-native-books&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My origins with the Cloud Native is originated from Kevin Hoffman&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native Go&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Go&lt;/a&gt;. I translated this book at the end of 2016. Since then, in China, the translation of the word &lt;code&gt;Cloud Native&lt;/code&gt; has not been determined, we introduced it with &lt;code&gt;云原生&lt;/code&gt; to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I begin to write the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook&#34; title=&#34;kubernetes-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;kubernetes-handbook&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub. So far, it has  more than 2000 stars. This book has written more than 200,000 Chinese characters, the first commit happened on April 14, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the the book Cloud Native Go completed, the publisher recommended another Cloud Native book to me -  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native Python&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Python&lt;/a&gt; by Manish Sethi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native Java&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Java&lt;/a&gt; by Josh Long and Kenny Bastani.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2018, with the hope that &lt;code&gt;Bring the world equal opportunities&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Building a Financial Cloud Native Infrastructure&lt;/code&gt;, I joined the &lt;a href=&#34;http://antfin.com&#34; title=&#34;Ant Group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ant Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;servicemesher-community&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time of May 2018, I start to organize the ServiceMesher community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we work with other open source communities in China, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.k8smeetup.com&#34; title=&#34;k8smeetup&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;k8smeetup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shardingjdbc.io/&#34; title=&#34;Sharding-Sphere&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sharding-Sphere&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://skywalking.apache.org/&#34; title=&#34;Apache SkyWalking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apache SkyWalking&lt;/a&gt;. Our community has grown to have 1,700 members and two round meetups in &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/blog/hangzhou-meetup-20180630/&#34; title=&#34;Hangzhou&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hangzhou&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/blog/beijing-meetup-20180729/&#34; title=&#34;Beijing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Beijing&lt;/a&gt; till now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 300 people participated in the scene and more than 20,000 people watched it live by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.itdks.com/eventlist/detail/2311&#34; title=&#34;IT 大咖说&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IT 大咖说&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future&#34;&gt;Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some hopes of mine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source culture become popular in China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More and more people would like to be involved in open source projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host one open source project into the CNCF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A book related to Cloud Native or Service Mesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen cultural exchanges between China and the global&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, welcome to China for traveling or share your topic with us on Cloud Native, and in the mean while we will share our experience on large scale web apps to the world. Hope to hear your voice!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
