<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jimmy Song</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:06:14 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Sandbox</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/cloud-native-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:06:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/cloud-native-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>Github: https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloud-native-sandbox
Cloud Native Sandbox can help you setup a standalone Kubernetes and istio environment with Docker on you own laptop.
The sandbox integrated with the following components:
 Kubernetes v1.10.3 Istio v1.0.4 Kubernetes dashboard v1.8.3  Differences with kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster As I have created the kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster to set up a Kubernetes cluster and istio service mesh with vagrantfile which consists of 1 master(also as node) and 3 nodes, but there is a big problem that it is so high weight and consume resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding How Envoy Sidecar Intercept and Route Traffic in Istio Service Mesh</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/understanding-how-envoy-sidecar-intercept-and-route-traffic-in-istio-service-mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 10:01:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/understanding-how-envoy-sidecar-intercept-and-route-traffic-in-istio-service-mesh/</guid>
      <description>This article uses Istio&amp;rsquo;s official bookinfo example to explain how Envoy performs routing forwarding after the traffic entering the Pod and forwarded to Envoy sidecar by iptables, detailing the inbound and outbound processing. For a detailed analysis of traffic interception, see Understanding Envoy Sidecar Proxy Injection and Traffic Interception in Istio Service Mesh .
The following is a request flow diagram for bookinfo officially provided by Istio, assuming that the DestinationRule is not configured in all services of the bookinfo application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native and me - the past, current and future</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/cloud-native-and-me-the-past-current-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:37:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/cloud-native-and-me-the-past-current-and-future/</guid>
      <description>Today I am honored to announce that I have become a CNCF Ambassador. Here is my story with Cloud Native. Origin The first time to attend the Cloud Native Computing Foundation is at the LC3 in Beijing 2017. I attended the meeting again this year, and in November of this year, CNCF will hold the KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon for the first time in Shanghai, China. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there too. LC3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SOFAMesh - A Solution for Large Scale Service Mesh based on Istio</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/introducing-sofamesh-a-solution-for-large-scale-service-mesh-by-ant-financial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 12:02:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/introducing-sofamesh-a-solution-for-large-scale-service-mesh-by-ant-financial/</guid>
      <description>SOFAMesh is a solution for large-scale Service Mesh based on Istio open-sourced by Ant Financial. At the same time it is also a part of SOFA(Scalable Open Financial Architecture) which is open sourced by Ant Financial too. On the basis of inheriting the powerful functions and rich features of Istio, in order to meet the performance requirements under large-scale deployment and to deal with the actual situation in the practice, the following improvements have been made:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Kubernetes Cluster With Vagrant and Virtualbox</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/setting-up-a-kubernetes-cluster-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 09:55:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/posts/setting-up-a-kubernetes-cluster-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>This doc is out-of-date, see at GitHub: https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster 使用Vagrant和VirtualBox在本地搭建分布式Kubernetes集群 - 中文 Using vagrant file to build a Kubernetes cluster which consists of 1 master(also as node) and 3 nodes. You</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>