
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – Waypoint</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/waypoint/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Waypoint on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Jimmy Song</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Jimmy Song</webMaster>
    
      <follow_challenge>
        <feedId>61582075856402432</feedId>
        <userId>59800919738273792</userId>
      </follow_challenge>
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 16:44:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/waypoint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
                                                         
    
                                                   
                           
    <item>
      <title>Understanding L7 Traffic Management in Istio Ambient Mode: From ztunnel to Waypoint Proxy</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 16:44:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In Istio&amp;rsquo;s ambient mode, &lt;strong&gt;ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt; acts as a node-level security proxy responsible for L4 traffic interception and encryption between services. However, ztunnel doesn’t handle L7 tasks such as HTTP-based routing or policy enforcement. For L7 traffic management, &lt;strong&gt;waypoint proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, powered by Envoy, processes HTTP requests and applies L7 policies. When ztunnel detects traffic requiring L7 processing, it forwards the traffic using the &lt;strong&gt;HBONE protocol&lt;/strong&gt; to the waypoint proxy. The proxy applies policies, logs telemetry data, and forwards requests to the target Pod through ztunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post details this traffic forwarding path, breaking down how L7 traffic flows from &lt;strong&gt;ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;waypoint proxy&lt;/strong&gt; and ultimately to the target Pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roles-and-responsibilities-in-ambient-mode&#34;&gt;Roles and Responsibilities in Ambient Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ztunnel-l4-traffic-manager&#34;&gt;ztunnel (L4 Traffic Manager)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intercepts traffic at L4 (TCP) level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secures traffic using mTLS encryption and authenticates service identities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;waypoint-proxy-l7-traffic-manager&#34;&gt;Waypoint Proxy (L7 Traffic Manager)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manages L7 traffic policies such as HTTP routing, authentication, authorization, and telemetry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acts as an application-aware proxy, applying business-specific policies and sending metrics to the observability stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a request requires L7 handling (e.g., &lt;code&gt;productpage&lt;/code&gt; service calling &lt;code&gt;reviews-v1&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;forwards traffic to waypoint proxy using HBONE&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling transparent policy application and telemetry collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;l7-traffic-path-in-ambient-mode&#34;&gt;L7 Traffic Path in Ambient Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagram illustrates the L7 traffic path in Istio ambient mode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/447f9e24cd3cc95eb700cbd7e0b62816.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/447f9e24cd3cc95eb700cbd7e0b62816.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;L7 Traffic Path in Ambient Mode&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;L7 Traffic Path in Ambient Mode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following two pictures respectively show the L7 traffic processing paths of the source Pod and the destination Pod in the same node and cross-node scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/hbone-same-node.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/hbone-same-node.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;L7 traffic path of source pod and destination pod on the same node&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;L7 traffic path of source pod and destination pod on the same node&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/hbone-cross-node.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/istio-ambient-l7-flow-analysis/hbone-cross-node.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;L7 traffic path of source pod and destination pod on different nodes&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;L7 traffic path of source pod and destination pod on different nodes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;traffic-path-breakdown&#34;&gt;Traffic Path Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-application-request-sent&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Application Request Sent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;productpage&lt;/code&gt; service initiates an HTTP request to the &lt;code&gt;reviews-v1&lt;/code&gt; service at &lt;code&gt;reviews.default.svc.cluster.local:9080&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-ztunnel-l4-traffic-interception&#34;&gt;2. ztunnel L4 Traffic Interception&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ztunnel on the source node intercepts the outbound request from &lt;code&gt;productpage&lt;/code&gt; using Kubernetes’ &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; rules. It inspects Istio&amp;rsquo;s control plane configuration and determines that L7 policies must be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-forwarding-traffic-using-hbone-protocol&#34;&gt;3. Forwarding Traffic Using HBONE Protocol&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ztunnel uses &lt;strong&gt;HBONE protocol&lt;/strong&gt; instead of native Envoy-to-Envoy XDS or TCP+mTLS tunneling. HBONE (HTTP-Based Overlay Network Environment) encapsulates traffic in HTTP/2, enabling transparent forwarding of traffic for L7 processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ztunnel wraps the intercepted traffic into an HBONE tunnel and forwards it to waypoint proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-l7-processing-and-policy-enforcement-by-waypoint-proxy&#34;&gt;4. L7 Processing and Policy Enforcement by Waypoint Proxy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waypoint proxy, built on Envoy, verifies the downstream client&amp;rsquo;s mTLS credentials using SPIFFE IDs and contextual metadata for authentication. It then applies the following policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP Routing &amp;amp; Load Balancing:&lt;/strong&gt; Routes requests based on Host/Path headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authorization Policies:&lt;/strong&gt; Validates access through headers and tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traffic Shaping:&lt;/strong&gt; Injects faults, rate-limits requests, and implements retries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telemetry Collection:&lt;/strong&gt; Tracks metrics, logs, traces, and request durations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waypoint proxy forwards the processed traffic through HBONE to the target node’s ztunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-delivering-traffic-to-target-pod&#34;&gt;5. Delivering Traffic to Target Pod&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ztunnel on the target node receives traffic from waypoint proxy through HBONE, decapsulates the request, and forwards it to the target Pod (&lt;code&gt;reviews-v1&lt;/code&gt;) on its application port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;insights-and-key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Insights and Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-transparent-routing-via-waypoint-proxy&#34;&gt;1. Transparent Routing via Waypoint Proxy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waypoint proxy&lt;/strong&gt; only knows the target Pod’s IP address and rewritten port &lt;code&gt;15008&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt; manages traffic redirection using Kubernetes &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-end-to-end-security&#34;&gt;2. End-to-End Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutual TLS (mTLS) with SPIFFE ID validation ensures secure traffic transmission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic &lt;strong&gt;cannot bypass ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt;, enforcing a &lt;strong&gt;Zero Trust Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-transparent-policy-enforcement&#34;&gt;3. Transparent Policy Enforcement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers don’t need to change the application code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic control, security, and telemetry are fully automated at the data plane level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-debug-ambient-mode&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Debug Ambient Mode?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ztunnel-debugging&#34;&gt;1. ztunnel Debugging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;istioctl ztunnel&lt;/code&gt; to inspect ztunnel configurations and states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-waypoint-proxy-debugging&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Waypoint Proxy Debugging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Envoy-specific commands such as &lt;code&gt;istioctl pc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;istioctl ps&lt;/code&gt; to inspect Envoy proxy configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;istioctl waypoint&lt;/code&gt; for streamlined configuration inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Istio ambient mode uses &lt;strong&gt;ztunnel&lt;/strong&gt; for L4 traffic processing, including transparent interception, mTLS encryption, and forwarding. L7 tasks such as HTTP-based routing, policy enforcement, and telemetry collection are managed by &lt;strong&gt;waypoint proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, with communication between ztunnel and waypoint proxy facilitated by &lt;strong&gt;HBONE protocol&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This innovative design eliminates sidecars, simplifying operations while maintaining high performance, security, and observability.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
