<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song - Cloud Native – Books</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Jimmy Song - Cloud Native</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-2022 Jimmy Song All Right Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Handbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/kubernetes-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/kubernetes-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes-handbookkubernetes-chinese-guidecloud-native-application-architecture-practice-manual&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Handbook——Kubernetes Chinese Guide/Cloud Native Application Architecture Practice Manual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book started in March 2017. It records my journey of learning and using Kubernetes from scratch. It focuses on experience sharing and summary. At the same time, it also has related concept analysis. I hope to help everyone step less and pit. The detour will also guide everyone to pay attention to the Kubernetes ecological surroundings, such as microservices construction, DevOps, big data applications, Service Mesh, Cloud Native and other fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kubernetes-handbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kubernetes Handbook by Jimmy Song&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;before-the-start&#34;&gt;Before the start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before reading this book, I hope you have the following knowledge and prepared the following environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux operating system principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux common commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker container principle and basic operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with internet access, Mac / Windows / Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-subject&#34;&gt;Book subject&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics of this book are not limited to Kubernetes, but also include the following major topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-native open source components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-native applications and microservices architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes-based Service Mesh architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes and microservices combined practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this book, all installed components, examples and operations are based on the &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes 1.6+&lt;/strong&gt; version. At the same time, we will pay close attention to Kubernetes version updates. As its version updates and upgrades, the Kubernetes version and examples in this book It will be updated accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this book in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/&#34;&gt;GitBook Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/releases&#34;&gt;Download the distribution of this book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;instructions to&lt;/a&gt; compile it offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fork a copy of your own notes to maintain it yourself, and those who have the power can join in together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: The Service Mesh related content in this book is no longer maintained, please go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com/istio-handbook&#34;&gt;istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt; to browse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn Kubernetes and cloud-native application architecture but do not want to build and configure a cluster yourself from scratch, you can directly use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster&#34;&gt;kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster&lt;/a&gt; project to directly deploy a 3-node distributed cluster and other such as Heapster , EFK, Istio and other optional components, or use a more lightweight &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloud-native-sandbox&#34;&gt;cloud-native-sandbox&lt;/a&gt; to run single-node Kubernetes, Istio and other components on a personal computer using Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributions-and-thanks&#34;&gt;Contributions and thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your contributions to this book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;View list of contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;See how to contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;View the organizational structure and use of the document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarkus Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In March 2021, &amp;ldquo;Quarkus Cookbook - A Java Solution Optimized for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; has been published by Machinery Industry Press and is available for purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;quarkus-cookbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Quarkus cookbook Chinese Edition&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;translators-preface&#34;&gt;Translator&#39;s Preface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quarkus is a new technology framework that is different from the traditional Java architecture. It is built on a familiar technology stack, using many proven technologies such as JPA, JAX-RS, Eclipse Vert.x, Eclipse MicroProfile and CDI, and integrating it with Kubernetes. Kubernetes and tightly integrated. Users can leverage Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; efficient scheduling operations and maintenance capabilities to maximize resource savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cloud-native flame has turned into a blaze of fire since the community Kubernetes burst into the limelight. Cloud-native related technologies are springing up. Yan Liu, Jingchao Song, and I are all members of the cloud-native community and love to preach about various related technologies, and are avid enthusiasts of this field. One of our common hobbies is to always keep an eye on good foreign technologies or excellent books on mature technologies released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process, we coincidentally found this book, which is not yet translated in China, and we set out to research Quarkus with enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book uses a very simple way to present problems, propose solutions, and trigger discussions, and portrays the technical points of Quarkus in a detailed and thorough way. With this book, users can learn the content on their own and use Quarkus to improve the productivity of Java-related R&amp;amp;D, making you invincible in the fast-paced world of microservice builds and cloud-based application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the translation process, we received full help from Huazhang Publishing and Editor Li Zhongming, and we would like to express our sincere thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we would like to thank you for having the chance to read this book, and hope that our three people&#39;s humble efforts can help you, who admire cloud-native technologies, to enjoy the same exhilaration as we do on the technical path of Quarkus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translated by Xiaoyu Zhang, Yan Liu, and Jimmy Song&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Patterns</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/images/books/cloud-native-patterns-jimmysong.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Native Patterns translated by Jimmy Song&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly are we talking about when we discuss cloud native? I&#39;ve been pondering this question over the years, and we may have different perspectives. Three years ago, I translated my first book on cloud native, and have been involved in the translation and creation of a series of cloud native works, as well as through participation in and observation of open source projects, communities, foundations, and application clouding in the cloud native space, I have come to the following conclusion: cloud native is a behavior and design philosophy, in essence, any behavior that can improve resource utilization and application delivery efficiency in the cloud or ways are cloud native. The history of cloud computing is a history of cloud-native biochemistry. Cloud native is the inevitable result of cloud computing adapting to the social division of labor, leaving system resources, underlying infrastructure, and application choreography to the cloud platform, and allowing developers to focus on business logic, which is exactly what cloud computing has been seeking for a long time. Cloud native applications, which seek to quickly build highly fault-tolerant and elastic distributed applications, the ultimate in R&amp;amp;D efficiency and a friendly go-live and maintenance experience, were born with the idea of cloud native, and they are inherently suited to be deployed in the cloud to maximize the dividends of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had previously translated several books on the subject of cloud-native, including Kevin Hoffman, author of Cloud Native Go, and Josh Long, author of Cloud Native Java, both of whom are from Pivotal or have worked at Pivotal for many years, and when I came across this book, I was surprised to find that the author Cornelia Davis is also from the same company, and Pivotal is really the Whampoa Military Academy of Cloud Natives. The content of this book is different from the previous Cloud Natives books, with a different approach to the model, so I immediately contacted Zhang Chunyu, the editor of the Electronic Industry Press. Java, my second collaboration with him, is really impressive in terms of the precision and efficiency with which he translated the book, and we each translated half of the book.
Everyone is talking about cloud-native, but they don&#39;t know exactly how to implement it. This book lists 12 patterns for building cloud-native applications, focusing on the data, services, and interactions of cloud-native applications, i.e., application-level design patterns, which are interspersed throughout the chapters in Part 2 of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to thank the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher community&lt;/a&gt;, members of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Community&lt;/a&gt;, and volunteers for their contribution to the development of cloud native in China, your encouragement and support is the driving force behind the continuous efforts and exploration in the field of cloud native. There are inevitably some mistakes in the translation of this book, and we hope readers will correct them.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This book is the Chinese version of &lt;em&gt;Cloud Native Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; , authors &lt;em&gt;Justin Garrison&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Kris Nova&lt;/em&gt; . The English version was released in November 2017 and is freely available on the Internet. This book is about creating and managing infrastructure for the whole life of cloud native applications. Models and practices of cycle management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, you will have the following gains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand why cloud-native infrastructure is necessary to run cloud-native applications efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use guidelines to decide when and whether your business should adopt cloud native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand patterns for deploying and managing infrastructure and applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design tests to prove that your infrastructure works as expected, even in a variety of edge situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to protect your infrastructure as a policy as a code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this book in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloud-native-infra&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/cloud-native-infra/&#34;&gt;Read the book online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/cloud-native-infrastructure/9781491984291/&#34;&gt;English original version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CloudNativeInfra/cni&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CloudNativeInfra/cni&lt;/a&gt; . Thanks to the original repository contributors for content organization and translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copyright of the English version of this book belongs to O&#39;Reilly, and the copyright of the Chinese version belongs to the publishing of the mechanical industry. It is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.zh&#34;&gt;attribution-non-commercial use-same sharing 4.0 (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)&lt;/a&gt; . It&#39;s about learning and consolidating cloud-native knowledge, and if necessary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://item.jd.com/12432007.html&#34;&gt;buy a paper book&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Handbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/serverless-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/serverless-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;serverless-handbook---a-practical-manual-for-serverless-architecture&#34;&gt;Serverless Handbook - A practical manual for serverless architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serverless (serverless architecture) means that the server-side logic is implemented by the developer, the application runs in a stateless computing container, is triggered by events, and is completely managed by a third party, and its business-level state is stored in a database or other medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serverless is an advanced stage in the development of cloud-native technologies that allows developers to focus more on business logic and reduce their focus on infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-book&#34;&gt;About this book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is the material compiled during my learning and practice of Serverless. At present, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative&#34;&gt;serverless&lt;/a&gt; open source project that is mainly concerned is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative&#34;&gt;Knative&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this book in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/serverless-handbook&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/serverless-handbook&#34;&gt;GitBook Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Engineering</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/google-engineering-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/google-engineering-practices/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Google has many common engineering practices that cover almost all languages and projects. This document is a long-term accumulation of best practices and the result of collective experience. We make it as public as possible, and your organization and open source projects will benefit as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following documents are currently included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Code Review Guidelines, in fact two sets of guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/eng-practices/docs/review/reviewer&#34;&gt;Code Reviewer&#39;s Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/eng-practices/docs/review/developer&#34;&gt;Code Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;translator-order&#34;&gt;Translator order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository is translated from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices&#34;&gt;google / eng-practices&lt;/a&gt; . The main content so far is Google ’s summary of how to conduct a &lt;strong&gt;Code Review&lt;/strong&gt; guide. Based on the title of the original Github repository, more Google engineering practices will be added later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github address of this document: https: //github.com/rootsongjc/eng-practices, click on the bottom of the page &lt;code&gt;Edit this page&lt;/code&gt;link to edit the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For other language versions, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eng-practices/eng-practices&#34;&gt;https://github.com/eng-practices/eng-practices&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/life1347&#34;&gt;Ta-Ching Chen&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translator: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This website is built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This website uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alex-shpak/hugo-book&#34;&gt;hugo-book&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documents in this project apply to the CC-By 3.0 license, which encourages you to share these documents. For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Architecture</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The first author of this book is Zhang Liang, now working at JD Finance. In order to enrich the content of the book, Zhang Liang asked my friends Wu Sheng, Ao Xiaojian, and me to co-author this grand proposition &amp;ldquo;The Future &amp;ldquo;Architecture&amp;rdquo;, the reason for the book he introduced is quoted below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-for-writing&#34;&gt;Reason for writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in the Internet industry, we have always been at the forefront of change and have been baptized by the world&#39;s tide. We keep chasing this wave of technology trends, and we will not fall behind the times. Especially in recent years, the Internet architecture has continuously evolved, undergoing a process from a centralized architecture to a distributed architecture to a cloud-native architecture. Cloud native has gradually become the protagonist of this era because it can solve the problems of slow upgrade of traditional applications, bloated architecture, and inability to quickly iterate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this wave of change, I watch it change the navigation direction of the Internet architecture, and bring new ideas and development to more and more companies and individuals. I have also used the road I have accumulated and accumulated over the years. Experience, and settled horizons to learn it, read it, and integrate it into my network of knowledge systems, to update the map of the brain that is constantly exploring and full of compass significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 and 2018, I went forward and backward with these changes, making Elastic-Job and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sharding-sphere&#34;&gt;Sharding-Sphere&lt;/a&gt; become recognized projects in the industry, making the open source projects I am responsible for international, and I have met more mentors and friends &amp;hellip; This kind of experience and development touched me to start writing down the beads of what I heard, what I saw, what I knew and what I felt, and formed this book in series: &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture-From Service to Cloud Native&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book contains the distributed, service-oriented, service grid, container, orchestration management, cloud native, cloud database you want to know &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book contains both my years of thoughtful insights and long-standing experience, as well as my struggle to give up and pick up, because I need to make the content of the book accountable to the reader &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is more exciting chapters of these Senior coffee narrative: Apache incubator project SkyWalking founder &amp;amp; APM expert Wu Sheng, CNCF Ambassador &amp;amp; cloud native preacher &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&lt;/a&gt; , Servicemesher community, co-founder &amp;amp; ServiceMesh preacher &lt;a href=&#34;https://skyao.io/&#34;&gt;Sky Ao&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: Cloud Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 Telecommunications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 Service Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 Observing Distributed Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 Intrusive Service Governance Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7 Kubernetes, the cornerstone of cloud native ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8 Cross-Language Service Governance Solution Service Mesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9 Cloud Native Data Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10. Distributed Database Middleware Ecosystem ShardingSphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suspense-wings&#34;&gt;Suspense wings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cover of the book is the background image of the Manchester United Holy Trinity statue standing in front of the Old Trafford Stadium selected by Teacher Zhang Liang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 6, 1958, after Manchester United participated in the Champions League in Yugoslavia to obtain the semi-finals, they encountered a Munich air crash on the way back, and the Manchester United team disappeared into the night sky instantly. For Manchester United&#39;s revival, the surviving Manchester United coach Matt Busby put up with grief and rebuilt Manchester United with blood, tears and sweat. On May 29, 1968, a full 10 years after the Munich air crash, Busby led his new team to finally win the UEFA Champions League, comforting those dead souls! This Holy Trinity statue becomes an eternal memorial!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faith, never giving up, perseverance, creating miracles, rebirth from fire &amp;hellip; is the strength I feel from this sculpture. Everyone will experience the peaks and valleys in their lives. I have seen mountains and deserts. I also hope that this book will not only bring you knowledge of the dry goods of the Internet architecture, but also my blessings to everyone: I hope that in this 100,000 Long March You, who are working tirelessly on the road, can have your own beliefs and hopes. Even if you have to go through countless deserts and oceans, you will be able to see the flowers after thousands of sails!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Java</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This is the third Cloud Native technical book I translated. The first two are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Go Chinese version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Python Chinese version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/images/books/jimmy-song-with-josh-long.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jimmy Song with Josh Long&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo taken on November 3, 2018, Beijing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-introduction&#34;&gt;Book Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s the difference between a traditional business and those like Amazon, Netflix and Etsy? These companies have well-established cloud-native development methods that allow them to stay ahead of their competitors. This practical guide shows Java / JVM developers how to build software faster and better with Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, and Cloud Foundry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations have set foot in the areas of cloud computing, test-driven development, microservices, and continuous integration and delivery. The authors of this book, Josh Long and Kenny Bastani, will take you deeper into these tools and methods and help you transform traditional applications into true cloud native applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book contains the following four sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basics&lt;/strong&gt; : Understand the motivations behind cloud-native thinking; configure and test Spring Boot applications; migrate your traditional applications to the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microservices&lt;/strong&gt; : use HTTP to build HTTP and RESTful services; route requests in distributed systems; establish edge services closer to data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data integration&lt;/strong&gt; : Use Spring Data to manage data and integrate distributed services with the event-driven, message-centric architecture supported by Spring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production&lt;/strong&gt; : Make your system observable; use service agents to connect to stateful services; understand the important ideas behind continuous delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are building a cloud native application, this book will be the basic guide to using the Java ecosystem. This book contains everything-the key tasks of building resilient services, managing data flow (through REST and asynchronous events), testing, deployment, and observability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;——Daniel Bryant&lt;/strong&gt; , software developer and CTO of SpectoLabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I predict that whether it is a cloud-native journey or a cloud-native goal, everyone involved will benefit from this cloud-native Java insight and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-Dr. Dava Syer&lt;/strong&gt; , contributor to Spring Framework, contributor and co-founder of Spring Boot and Spring Cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;author-information&#34;&gt;author information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Long&lt;/strong&gt; is a Spring evangelist, editor of InfoQ.com&#39;s Java queue, and lead author of several books including Spring Recipes Second Edition (published by Apress). Josh has spoken at many international industry conferences, including TheServiceSide Java Symposium, SpringOne, OSCON, JavaZone, Devoxx, Java2Days, and more. When he was not writing SpringSource code, he was either in the Java user group or drinking coffee in a coffee shop. Josh likes solutions that drive technology forward. His interests include scalability, BPM, grid computing, mobile computing, and so-called &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; systems. You can browse his blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.springsource.org/&#34;&gt;http://blog.springsource.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://joshlong.com/&#34;&gt;http://joshlong.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenny Bastani&lt;/strong&gt; is a Spring evangelist at Pivotal. As an open source contributor and blogger, Kenny focuses on graph databases, microservices, and more, and enjoys attracting a group of passionate software developers. Kenny is also a frequent guest at industry conferences such as OSCON, SpringOne Platform, and GOTO. He maintains a &lt;a href=&#34;http://kennybastani.com/&#34;&gt;personal blog&lt;/a&gt; on software architecture and provides tutorials and open source reference examples for building event-driven microservices and serverless architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface (James Watters) xvii&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prologue (Rod Johnson) xix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface xxi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I Basic Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 Cloud Native Applications 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2. Boot Camp: Spring Boot and Cloud Foundry 21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 Configurations in a Twelve-Factor Program Style 67&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 Testing 85&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 Migrating Legacy Applications 115&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part II Web Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 The REST API 137&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7 Routing 179&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8 Edge Services 197&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part III Data Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9 Data Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10 The Message System 303&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11 Batches and Tasks 325&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12 Data Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part IV Production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13 Observable Systems 411&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 14 Service Agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 15 Continuous Delivery 497&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix to Part V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix A Using Spring Boot 527 in Java EE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Python</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Go&lt;/a&gt; after yet another masterpiece on Cloud Native been boarded my writing schedule, this is Python-based services and cloud build micro-native Web applications, the title is called Cloud Native Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this book overlaps with Cloud Native Go, and the directory structure is basically the same. The technology stack used is similar, but the content is more detailed, the pictures and steps are introduced more, and the other one I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/posts/book-kubernetes-management-design-patterns/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Management Design Patterns: With Docker, CoreOS Linux, and Other Platforms&lt;/a&gt; written by Indians are very similar in style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-native-python-introduction&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Python Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of business today, in order to support the rapid expansion of enterprises, it is not enough to simply use their own infrastructure. As a result, they have been pursuing the resilience of the cloud to build platforms that support highly scalable applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book can help you understand everything you need to build a cloud-native application architecture with Python in one stop. In this book we first introduce you to cloud-native application architectures and what problems they can help you solve. Then you will learn how to build microservices using REST API and Python, and build a web layer in an event-driven way. Next, you will learn how to interact with data services and build web views using React, after which we will detail the security and performance of the application. Then, you will learn how to Docker containerize your services. Finally, you will learn how to deploy your application on AWS and Azure platforms. After you have deployed your application, we will end this book around a series of concepts and techniques about application troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-covered-in-this-book&#34;&gt;What is covered in this book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 introduces cloud-native application architecture and microservices, discusses the basic concepts of cloud-native architecture, and builds application development environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 uses Python to build microservices, build your own microservices knowledge base, and expand based on your use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 uses Python to build web applications, build an initial web application, and integrate with microservices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4, Interacting with Data Services, teaches you how to migrate applications to different database services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 Building Web Views with React.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 uses Flux to create extensible UIs to help you understand how to use Flux to create extensible applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7, Event Tracing and CQRS, discusses how to store contracts in the form of events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8 Protect Web Applications from External Threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9 is related to continuous delivery and frequent application releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10, Docker Containerizing Your Services, discusses container services and running applications in Docker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11 Deploying Applications to the AWS Platform teaches you how to build infrastructure on AWS and set up a production environment for your applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12, Deploying Applications to the Azure Platform, discusses how to build infrastructure on Azure and set up a production environment for your applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13, Monitoring Cloud Applications, understands monitoring tools for different infrastructures and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-tools-and-environments-do-you-need-to-use-this-book&#34;&gt;What tools and environments do you need to use this book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to have Python installed on your system. A text editor, preferably Vim, Sublime or Notepad ++. In one chapter you need to download POSTMAN, a powerful API test suite that can be installed as a Chrome extension. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/postman/fhbjgbiflinjbdggehcddcbncdddomop?hl=en&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/postman/fhbjgbiflinjbdggehcddcbncdddomop?hl=en&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, if you have the following website account, it is even better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience&#34;&gt;Target audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is intended for developers who have a basic knowledge of Python and are familiar with the basic principles of the command line and HTTP-based applications. This book is ideal for those who want to learn how to build, test, and extend applications developed in Python. No previous experience in building microservices with Python is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-info&#34;&gt;More info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Cloud Native Go, please refer to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Go-A guide to building web cloud services based on Go and React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Cloud Native, please refer to this Pivotal booklet I translated &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34;&gt;to the cloud native application architecture-Chinese version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Cloud Native ecology, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native&#34;&gt;awesome-cloud-native&lt;/a&gt; I organized&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/awesome-cloud-native)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Handbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/docker-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/docker-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;docker-handbook&#34;&gt;Docker Handbook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a prequel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Handbook&lt;/a&gt; . This book mainly introduces the new features of Docker 1.13 and helps you understand the management and use of Docker clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/docker-handbook&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rootsongjc/docker-handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit online address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/docker-handbook&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/docker-handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The container is the best carrier for microservices. Kubernetes is the best platform for &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/&#34;&gt;microservices.&lt;/a&gt; Istio is the best service mesh on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2017, the Docker project was renamed moby. In October, DockerCon announced in Copenhagen that Docker Company embraced Kubernetes. Kubernetes has become the de facto king in the container orchestration field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;Notice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book cites and organizes some public sharing and links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This book was written in early 2017 and is no longer updated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Handbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/hugo-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/hugo-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;manual-for-static-website-building---building-a-personal-blog-with-hugo&#34;&gt;Manual for static website building - Building a personal blog with Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This manual will guide you how to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo to&lt;/a&gt; build a static website for personal blog or project display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach you how to build a static website from scratch. This does not require much programming and development experience and time investment, and basically does not require much cost (except for personalized domain names). Use GitHub and Hugo templates to quickly build and Launch a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online browsing address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/hugo-handbook&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/hugo-handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-audience&#34;&gt;Target audience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document is for the following users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who don&#39;t know much about website building, and have no experience in web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who want to build a website quickly, have few personalization needs, don&#39;t want to spend too much energy to take care of, and update not many users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who want to learn website construction, website template, web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who are interested in Go and want to work on open source projects 项目&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributor&#34;&gt;Contributor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt; to this book .&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Go</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Kevin Hoffman &amp;amp; Dan Nemeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translators: Song Jingchao, Wu Yingsong, Xu Bei, Ma Chao&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publisher: Electronic Industry Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full name: Cloud Native Go-A guide to building web cloud native applications based on Go and React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has been published by the Electronic Industry Press and can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://item.m.jd.com/product/12123347.html&#34;&gt;purchased on JD.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/images/books/jimmy-song-with-kevein-hoffman.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jimmy Song with Kevin Hoffman&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo taken on September 12, 2017, Beijing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native Go shows developers how to build large-scale cloud applications that, while meeting the strong needs of today&#39;s customers, can dynamically scale to handle data volumes, traffic, or users of almost any size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Hoffman and Dan Nemeth describe modern cloud-native applications in detail, clarifying factors, rules, and habits related to rapid and reliable cloud-native development. They also introduced Go as a &amp;ldquo;simple and elegant&amp;rdquo; high-performance language, which is particularly suitable for cloud development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this book you will use Go to create microservices, use ReactJS and Flux to add front-end web components, and master advanced cloud-native technologies based on Go. Hoffman and Nemeth show how to use tools such as Wercker, Docker, and Dockerhub to build a continuous delivery pipeline; automatically push applications to the platform; and systematically monitor application performance in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &amp;ldquo;The Way of the Cloud&amp;rdquo;: Why Developed Cloud Software Is Basically About Mindset and Rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn why using Go is ideal for cloud-native microservices development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for cloud applications that support continuous delivery and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design the service ecosystem and then build them in a test-first manner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push ongoing work to the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use event sources and CQRS mode to respond to large scale and high throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure cloud-based web applications: the choice between what to do and what not to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a responsive cloud application with a third-party messaging vendor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build large-scale, cloud-friendly GUIs with React and Flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor dynamic scaling, failover and fault tolerance in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-author&#34;&gt;About the author&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Hoffman&lt;/strong&gt; helps businesses bring their applications to the cloud by modernizing and building cloud-native services in many different languages. He started programming at the age of 10 and taught himself BASIC on the reassembled Commodore VIC-20. Since then, he has been obsessed with building software and has spent a lot of time learning languages, frameworks, and patterns. He has built a range of software from remote-control photography drones, bionic security systems, ultra-low-latency financial applications to mobile applications. He fell in love with the Go language when building custom components that needed to work with Pivotal Cloud Foundry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin is the author of the popular Fantasy Book series ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2fc8iES&#34;&gt;The Sigilord Chronicles&lt;/a&gt; ), and he is eagerly looking forward to finally combining his love of building software with his love of building fantasy worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Nemeth&lt;/strong&gt; currently works as a consulting solutions architect at Pivotal, where he supports Pivotal Cloud Foundry. He has been developing software since Commodore 64, has been professionally coding since 1995, and has written CGI scripts for local ISPs using ANSIC. Since then, he has spent most of his career as an independent consultant providing solutions for everything from finance to the pharmaceutical industry, using a variety of languages and frameworks that were popular at the time. Dan recently accepted Go as his destination and passionately used it for all projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that Dan is not at the computer, he is probably playing sailing or fly fishing in the waters near Annapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: The Way of Clouds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 Start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 Getting Started with Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 Continuous Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 Building Microservices in Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 Using Backend Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7 Building Data Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8 Event Tracing and CQRS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9 Building Web Applications with Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10 Cloud Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11 Using WebSockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12 Building Web Views with React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13 Building Scalable UIs with Flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 14 Creating a Complete Application World of FluxCraft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 15 Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix A Troubleshooting for Cloud Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Cloud Native</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This book is the Chinese version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://content.pivotal.io/ebooks/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34;&gt;Migrating to Cloud Native Application Architectures&lt;/a&gt; . The English version of this book was released in February 2015. The Chinese version was translated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&lt;/a&gt; and published in July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34;&gt;Gitbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;translator-order&#34;&gt;Translator order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud-native applications in the cloud era have come. Are you ready to migrate traditional monolithic applications to cloud-native architectures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;consciousness determines action&amp;rdquo;, before moving to cloud native applications, we all need to have a general understanding of Cloud Native (cloud native) concept, organizational form, and technology to implement it, so as to guide our cloud Native architecture practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pivotal.io/&#34;&gt;Pivotal&lt;/a&gt; is the author of cloud-native applications, and launched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pivotal.io/platform&#34;&gt;Pivotal Cloud Foundry&lt;/a&gt; cloud-native application platform and &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/&#34;&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt; open source Java development framework, becoming a pioneer and pathfinder in cloud-native application architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original book was written in 2015. The examples in it are mainly for Java applications, but they are also applicable to any application type. The cloud-native application architecture is suitable for program development in heterogeneous languages, not just for Java language program development. As I translated the book, the cloud-native applications ecosystem has begun to take shape, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cncf.io/&#34;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt; members continue to grow and develop, based on Cloud Native start-up companies emerging, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; to lead the trend of container arrangement, and Service Mesh technology (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkerd.io/&#34;&gt;Linkerd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/&#34;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt; ) of Appears, the rise of the Go language (refer to another book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Go&lt;/a&gt; ), etc., provides more options for us to migrate our applications to the cloud native architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, many enterprises are adopting cloud-native application architecture, which can help their IT transformation and become a real agile force in market competition. O&#39;Reilly&#39;s report defines the characteristics of cloud-native application architectures, such as microservices and twelve-factor applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author of this book, Matt Stine, also explores the cultural, organizational, and technological changes required to migrate traditional monolithic and service-oriented architecture (SOA) applications to cloud-native architectures. There is also a migration manual in this book that contains methods for breaking monolithic applications into microservices, implementing fault tolerance models, and performing automated testing of cloud-native services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application architectures discussed in this book include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twelve-factor application: A collection of cloud-native application architecture patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservices: independently deployed services, each service does one thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-service agile infrastructure: a platform that provides application environments and back-office services quickly, repeatably, and consistently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API-based collaboration: published and versioned APIs that allow interactions between services in a cloud-native application architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure resistance: a system that becomes stronger under pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-author&#34;&gt;About the author&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Stine, Technical Product Manager at Pivotal, has 15 years of experience in corporate IT and many business areas. Matt emphasizes lean / agile methods, DevOps, architectural patterns, and programming paradigms, and he is exploring the use of technology portfolios to help enterprise IT departments work like startups.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio Handbook</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;istio-handbookistio-advanced-practice-of-istio-service-mesh&#34;&gt;Istio Handbook——Istio Advanced Practice of Istio Service Mesh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Istio Service Mesh Advanced Practical - Master the Services in Post Kubernetes Era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt; is a service mesh framework jointly developed by Google, IBM, Lyft, etc., and began to enter the public vision in early 2017. As an important infrastructure layer that inherits Kubernetes and connects to the serverless architecture in the cloud-native era, Istio is of crucial importance important. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com/&#34;&gt;The ServiceMesher community,&lt;/a&gt; as one of the earliest open source communities in China that is researching and promoting Service Mesh technology, decided to integrate community resources and co-author an open source e-book as a service mesh think tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read or participate in this book at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com/istio-handbook&#34;&gt;Gitbook online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-book&#34;&gt;About this book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book originates from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/istio-handbook&#34;&gt;rootsongjc/istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-knowledge-map&#34;&gt;Istio knowledge map&lt;/a&gt; created by the ServiceMesher community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is based on Istio 1.0+ and includes, but is not limited to , topics in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-knowledge-map&#34;&gt;Istio Knowledge Graph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;copyright&#34;&gt;copyright&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The publishing copyright of this book belongs to the blog post of Electronic Industry Press. Please do not print and distribute it without authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;participate-in-the-book&#34;&gt;Participate in the book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;writing specifications of this book&lt;/a&gt; and join the Slack channel discussion after joining ServiceMesher.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
