<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – Library</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Library on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio in Action</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-action/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;editors-recommendation&#34;&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s Recommendation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The authors of this book are global experts in service mesh technology, providing comprehensive and detailed content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The translators of this book are technical experts from the domestic cloud-native community, striving to convey the content accurately and providing localization for difficult-to-understand concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book covers comprehensive content, including the latest versions and core concepts of Istio, with rich and complete example codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-action/cover_hu9360058b8093bde4e3238be90b0433a1_76712_800x772_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-action/cover.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/istio-in-action/cover.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;800&#34; data-height=&#34;772&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Istio in Action (Chinese edition)&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Istio in Action (Chinese edition)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a representative product of service mesh technology, Istio has matured over the years and is increasingly favored by developers. This book focuses on Istio service mesh, covering basic concepts, core features, operations, and enterprise-level implementations. From basic installation and deployment to practical functions, from analyzing underlying principles to troubleshooting, and from advanced operations to enterprise-level practices, it provides a comprehensive introduction to various aspects of Istio service mesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is suitable for developers, operations engineers, architects, and other practitioners in the cloud-native field who are currently using or interested in Istio. Whether you are a beginner in service mesh technology or an expert in the field, you can find theoretical insights and practical guidance in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-authors&#34;&gt;About the Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian Posta is the Chief Technology Officer for Global Field at Solo.io. He is well-known in the cloud-native community as an author, blogger, speaker, and contributor to various open-source projects in the service mesh and cloud-native ecosystem. With experience working in both traditional enterprises and large internet companies, Christian now helps organizations create and deploy large-scale, cloud-native, resilient distributed architectures. He specializes in guiding, training, and leading teams to success in distributed systems concepts, microservices, DevOps, and cloud-native application design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinor Maloku is an engineer at Solo.io, providing consulting services to clients adopting application networking solutions such as service mesh. Previously, he worked at Red Hat, where he developed middleware software that enabled development teams to ensure the high availability of their services. As a freelancer, he has served several DAX 30 members to fully leverage the potential of cloud computing technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-translators&#34;&gt;About the Translators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma Ruofei works as Chief Engineer at FreeWheel Beijing R&amp;amp;D Center, primarily responsible for microservices architecture design and cloud-native landing work. He is the author of &amp;ldquo;Istio Practical Guide,&amp;rdquo; columnist for GeekTime&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Service Mesh in Action,&amp;rdquo; and the main author of &amp;ldquo;Cloud-Native Application Architecture: Best Practices for Microservices Development.&amp;rdquo; He is also an IT professional book expert consultant for People&amp;rsquo;s Posts and Telecommunications Press, as well as a member of the ServiceMesher technical community and the Cloud Native Community management committee. He has published and translated numerous articles on cutting-edge technologies in the cloud-native field and is passionate about technology sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Song Jingchao (Jimmy Song) is a Developer Advocate at Tetrate, the founder of the cloud-native community, and the former Developer Advocate and Open Source Manager at Ant Group. He is also a published author and independent writer. He is an early adopter and promoter of open-source technologies such as Kubernetes and Istio. He has authored books such as &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture: From Service to Cloud-Native&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Understanding Istio: Advanced Practical Guide to Cloud-Native Service Mesh&amp;rdquo; and has participated in the translation of many works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luo Guangming is an architect at ByteDance&amp;rsquo;s Service Framework Team, a member and Beijing stationmaster of the Cloud Native Community management committee. He has previously worked on cloud-native, microservices, and open-source-related projects at Ericsson and Baidu before joining ByteDance, where he is responsible for open-source projects related to microservices like CloudWeGo. He has been focusing on cutting-edge technologies, architectural evolution, and standardization processes in the cloud-native and microservices fields for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Istio: Advanced Practices in Cloud Native Service Mesh</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;achieving-open-source-in-the-name-of-community&#34;&gt;Achieving Open Source in the Name of Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2018, with the support of Ant Group, the ServiceMesher community was established. Subsequently, a whirlwind of service mesh swept across China, and the community-led translation work of the official Istio documentation entered a fervent stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went on, I felt the lack of comprehensive Chinese materials introducing Istio. Therefore, in September 2018, I began conceptualizing a book about Istio and initiated the open-source e-book project &amp;ldquo;Istio Handbook&amp;rdquo; on GitHub. Several months later, with the promotion of service mesh technology and the expansion of the ServiceMesher community, I met many friends who were also passionate about Istio and service mesh technology through online and offline activities in the community. We unanimously decided to write an open-source e-book about Istio together, compiling valuable articles and experiences accumulated by the community into a systematic text to share with developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2019, under the organization of the community&amp;rsquo;s management committee, dozens of members volunteered to participate and jointly write this book. In May 2020, to better promote cloud native technology and enrich the technical content shared by the community, we established the Cloud Native Community and incorporated the original ServiceMesher community into it. The content operated by the community also expanded from service mesh technology to a more comprehensive range of cloud native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2020, the main contributors to this book formed the editorial committee, including myself, Ma Ruofei, Wang Bai Ping, Wang Wei, Luo Guangming, Zhao Huabing, Zhong Hua, and Guo Xudong. With the guidance and assistance of the publisher, we carried out subsequent version upgrades, improvements, and optimizations for this book. After repeated iterations, this book &amp;ldquo;Understanding Istio: Advanced Practices in Cloud Native Service Mesh&amp;rdquo; finally met with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover_hube4bdbab8f283103248e147e4ddb4177_139900_1200x1569_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;1200&#34; data-height=&#34;1569&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Book cover&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Book cover&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-book&#34;&gt;About This Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After version 1.5, Istio underwent significant architectural changes and introduced or improved multiple features, such as introducing intelligent DNS proxy, new resource objects, and improving support for virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is based on the new versions of Istio and strives to provide readers with the latest and most comprehensive content while continuously tracking the latest trends in the Istio community. Additionally, many authors of this book are frontline developers or operation engineers with rich practical experience in Istio, providing valuable reference cases for this book.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarkus in Action</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;translators-foreword&#34;&gt;Translator&amp;rsquo;s Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Quarkus in Action: Java Solutions Optimized for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; is authored by Alex Soto Bueno and Jason Porter, translated by Zhang Xiaoyu, Liu Yan, and Song Jingchao, and published by Machinery Industry Press in March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/quarkus-cookbook_hu20748ed953ea51ac1a2e6ce67ae2862a_596251_2000x1259_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/quarkus-cookbook.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/quarkus-cookbook/quarkus-cookbook.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;2000&#34; data-height=&#34;1259&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Quarkus Cookbook in Action&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Quarkus Cookbook in Action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quarkus is a new technology framework that differs from traditional Java architectures. It builds upon familiar technology stacks, utilizing mature technologies such as JPA, JAX-RS, Eclipse Vert.x, Eclipse MicroProfile, and CDI, tightly integrated with Kubernetes. Users can leverage Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; efficient scheduling and operational capabilities to maximize resource savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spark of cloud-native technology, ignited by the popularity of the Kubernetes community, has grown into a raging fire. Cloud-native-related technologies are emerging like mushrooms after the rain. Liu Yan, Song Jingchao, and I are all members of the cloud-native community and enthusiasts who love to promote various related technologies. One of our common interests is to keep an eye on the release of excellent books on foreign or mature technologies in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this process, we coincidentally discovered this book, which had not been translated in China yet. With great enthusiasm, we embarked on the journey of studying Quarkus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book portrays the technical aspects of Quarkus in a detailed and thorough manner by presenting questions, proposing solutions, and sparking discussions. Through this book, users can self-learn relevant content and improve the efficiency of Java-related development work with Quarkus, enabling them to stand firm in the fast-paced fields of microservice construction and cloud-based application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the entire translation process, we received full support from HuaZhong Publishing House and Editor Li Zhongming, for which we express our heartfelt gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, thank you all for having the opportunity to read this book. We hope that our efforts can help you, who advocate for cloud-native technology, enjoy the same joy as us on the technical path of Quarkus.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Patterns</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Patterns,&amp;rdquo; authored by Cornelia Davis, translated by Zhang Ruofei and Song Jingchao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in August 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/cloud-native-patterns_hu53442bc8a5df1347cc048c02a27fccf1_119191_610x800_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/cloud-native-patterns.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/cloud-native-patterns/cloud-native-patterns.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;610&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cover of the book Cloud Native Patterns&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of the book Cloud Native Patterns&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly are we talking about when we discuss cloud-native? I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering this question for years, and perspectives may vary. Since translating the first book on cloud-native three years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in translating and creating a series of works on cloud-native. Through participation in and observation of open-source projects, communities, foundations, and the process of application cloudification in the cloud-native field, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion: cloud-native is a way of behavior and design philosophy. Essentially, any behavior or method that can improve resource utilization and application delivery efficiency in the cloud is cloud-native. The history of cloud computing is a history of cloud-native transformation. Cloud-native is the inevitable result of cloud computing adapting to social division of labor, entrusting system resources, underlying infrastructure, and application orchestration to cloud platforms, allowing developers to focus on business logic. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this what cloud computing has been striving for all along? Cloud-native applications pursue the rapid construction of highly fault-tolerant, elastic distributed applications, striving for the ultimate development efficiency and friendly online and operational experience. With the concept of cloud-native, born to be deployed in the cloud, they can maximize the dividends brought by cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this, I translated several books on cloud-native topics, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/&#34; title=&#34;&amp;amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Go&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Go&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
 by Kevin Hoffman and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/&#34; title=&#34;&amp;amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Java&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Java&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
 by Josh Long. They both come from Pivotal or have worked at Pivotal for many years. When I saw this book, I was surprised to find that the author, Cornelia Davis, also comes from this company. Pivotal is truly the cradle of cloud-native. The content of this book is different from previous cloud-native books, innovatively organizing patterns, so I immediately contacted Zhang Chunyu, the editor of Publishing House of Electronics Industry. He informed me that Zhang Ruofei was translating this book. Previously, I had cooperated with him to translate &amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Java.&amp;rdquo; This book is our second collaboration, and I truly admire his accuracy and efficiency in translating books. We each translated half of the content of this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is discussing cloud-native, but how to implement it is still a matter of debate. This book lists 12 patterns for building cloud-native applications, mainly focusing on data, services, and interactions of cloud-native applications, namely, design patterns at the application level. These patterns are interspersed throughout the chapters of the second part of this book, covering various aspects of cloud-native applications, and combining theory with practice, guiding readers to implement a cloud-native application using Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to express my gratitude to the members and volunteers of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native Community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Community&lt;/a&gt;
 for their contributions to the development of cloud-native in China. Your encouragement and support are the driving force behind continuous efforts and exploration in the field of cloud-native. There may be some omissions in the translation process of this book, and I hope readers can point them out.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native,&amp;rdquo; authored by Zhang Liang, Wu Sheng, Ao Xiao Jian, and Song Jingchao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture_hud60a11f0910ecceebc3b7ea1a5832fc1_141425_610x800_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;610&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cover of the book Future Architecture&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of the book Future Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first author of this book is Zhang Liang, currently working at JD Finance. To enrich the content of the book, Zhang Liang invited his friends in the industry, Wu Sheng, Ao Xiao Jian, and myself, to co-author this ambitious work on &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture.&amp;rdquo; Below is an excerpt of his introduction to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origin-of-the-book&#34;&gt;Origin of the Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As professionals in the internet industry, we have always been at the forefront of change, constantly chasing the waves of technological advancement to avoid falling behind the pace of the times. Especially in recent years, internet architecture has undergone continuous evolution, transitioning from centralized architecture to distributed architecture, and then to cloud-native architecture. Cloud-native architecture has gradually become the protagonist of this era because it can address issues such as slow application upgrades, bloated architectures, and inability to iterate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of this wave of change, I watched as it altered the course of internet architecture and brought new ideas and developments to more and more companies and individuals. I embarked on a journey to learn and understand it, integrating it into my knowledge system to update the architectural map in my mind with the experiences and insights accumulated over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 and 2018, I experienced these changes firsthand, making projects like Elastic-Job and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/shardingsphere&#34; title=&#34;Sharding-Sphere&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sharding-Sphere&lt;/a&gt;
 widely recognized in the industry, internationalizing the open-source projects I was responsible for, and meeting more mentors and friends. These experiences inspired me to put what I heard, saw, knew, and felt onto paper, connecting them into this book: &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book covers everything you want to know about distributed systems, service-oriented architecture, service mesh, containers, orchestration, cloud-native, and cloud databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It contains my well-considered insights and experiences accumulated over the years, as well as my struggles of abandoning and picking up the pen again because I feel responsible for the content of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also features chapters contributed by seasoned experts in the field, including Wu Sheng, the founder of Apache Incubator project SkyWalking and an APM expert; Song Jingchao, a CNCF Ambassador, cloud-native evangelist, and founder of the Cloud-Native Community; and Ao Xiao Jian, a service mesh evangelist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: Cloud-Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2: Remote Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3: Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4: Service Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5: Observing Distributed Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6: Intrusive Service Governance Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7: Kubernetes: The Cornerstone of Cloud-Native Ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8: Cross-Language Service Governance Solutions: Service Mesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9: Cloud-Native Data Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10: Distributed Database Middleware Ecosystem: ShardingSphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wings-of-aspiration&#34;&gt;Wings of Aspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The back cover of the book features the Holy Trinity statue standing in front of Old Trafford Stadium, chosen by Professor Zhang Liang as the background image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 6, 1958, while returning from Yugoslavia after securing a spot in the European Cup semi-finals, the Manchester United team encountered the Munich air disaster, disappearing in the night sky. To revive Manchester United, surviving manager Matt Busby rebuilt the team with blood, tears, and sweat. Exactly 10 years after the Munich air disaster, on May 29, 1968, Busby led his new team to finally lift the European Cup, comforting the souls of those who had passed away! The Holy Trinity statue became an eternal memorial!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faith, resilience, perseverance, miracles, and rebirth&amp;hellip; These are the strengths I feel from this sculpture. Everyone will experience peaks and valleys, see mountains and deserts in their lifetime, and I hope this book not only brings practical knowledge of internet architecture but also embodies my blessings to you all: I hope that amidst the relentless struggles on this long journey, you can have your own faith and hope, and even after traversing countless deserts and oceans, you can see the light after experiencing numerous trials!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Java</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Java,&amp;rdquo; authored by Josh Long, translated by Zhang Ruofei and Song Jingchao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/cloud-native-java_hu53442bc8a5df1347cc048c02a27fccf1_94349_610x800_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/cloud-native-java.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/cloud-native-java/cloud-native-java.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;610&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cover of the book Cloud Native Java&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of the book Cloud Native Java&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/jimmy-song-with-josh-long_huea3c791af24fc641d73e0c4c834fe1e3_185537_1200x800_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-java/jimmy-song-with-josh-long.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/cloud-native-java/jimmy-song-with-josh-long.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;1200&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jimmy Song with Josh Long&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jimmy Song with Josh Long&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo taken on November 3, 2018, in Beijing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-introduction&#34;&gt;Book Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What distinguishes traditional enterprises from companies like Amazon, Netflix, and Etsy? These companies have perfected cloud-native development methods that enable them to stay ahead and lead the competition. This practical guide shows Java/JVM developers how to build software faster and better using Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, and Cloud Foundry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations have already ventured into cloud computing, test-driven development, microservices, and continuous integration and delivery. Authors Josh Long and Kenny Bastani will take you deep into these tools and practices, helping you transform traditional applications into true cloud-native ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book consists of four major parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;: Understand the motivation behind cloud-native thinking; configure and test Spring Boot applications; migrate your traditional applications to the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microservices&lt;/strong&gt;: Build HTTP and RESTful services using Spring; route requests in distributed systems; establish edge services closer to data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Manage data using Spring Data and integrate distributed services with Spring-supported event-driven, message-centric architectures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production&lt;/strong&gt;: Make your system observable; use service proxies to connect stateful services; understand the important ideas behind continuous delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re building cloud-native applications, this book will serve as your essential guide to using the Java ecosystem. It covers everything—building resilient services, managing data flows (via REST and asynchronous events), testing, deployment, and observability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—Daniel Bryant&lt;/strong&gt;, Software Developer and CTO at SpectoLabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out on your cloud-native journey or nearing your cloud-native goals, everyone involved will benefit from the insights and experiences shared in this Cloud Native Java book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—Dr. Dave Syer&lt;/strong&gt;, Contributor to the Spring Framework, and Co-founder of Spring Boot and Spring Cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-authors&#34;&gt;About the Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Long&lt;/strong&gt; is a Spring Developer Advocate, an editor at InfoQ.com&amp;rsquo;s Java queue, and the primary author of several books, including the second edition of Spring Recipes (published by Apress). Josh has spoken at many international industry conferences, including TheServiceSide Java Symposium, SpringOne, OSCON, JavaZone, and Devoxx, among others. When he&amp;rsquo;s not writing code for SpringSource, he&amp;rsquo;s either at a Java User Group meeting or in a coffee shop. Josh loves solutions that push technology forward. His interests include scalability, BPM, grid computing, mobile computing, and so-called &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; systems. You can browse his blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.springsource.org/&#34; title=&#34;http://blog.springsource.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://blog.springsource.org&lt;/a&gt;
 or &lt;a href=&#34;http://joshlong.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://joshlong.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://joshlong.com&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenny Bastani&lt;/strong&gt; is a Spring Developer Advocate at Pivotal. As an open-source contributor and blogger, Kenny focuses on graph databases, microservices, and attracting a passionate group of software developers. Kenny is also a regular attendee at industry conferences such as OSCON, SpringOne Platform, and GOTO. He maintains a &lt;a href=&#34;http://kennybastani.com/&#34; title=&#34;personal blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;personal blog&lt;/a&gt;
 about software architecture and provides tutorials and open-source reference examples for building event-driven microservices and serverless architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword (James Watters) xvii&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword (Rod Johnson) xix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface xxi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I Foundations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 Cloud-Native Applications 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 Bootcamp: Spring Boot and Cloud Foundry 21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 Configuration, as Twelve-Factor Style 67&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 Testing 85&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 Migrating Legacy Applications 115&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part II Web Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 REST API 137&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7 Routing 179&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8 Edge Services 197&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part III Data Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9 Data Management 251&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10 Messaging Systems 303&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11 Batch Processing and Tasks 325&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12 Data Integration 363&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part IV Production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13 Observable Systems 411&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 14 Service Proxies 469&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 15 Continuous Delivery 497&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part V Appendix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix A Using Spring Boot in Java EE 527&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Python</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Python,&amp;rdquo; authored by Marish Sethi, translated by Song Jingchao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in July 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of Cloud Native Python&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-cloud-native-python&#34;&gt;Introduction to Cloud Native Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With today&amp;rsquo;s rapid business development, relying solely on their own infrastructure is far from enough for enterprises to support their rapid expansion. Therefore, they have been pursuing the elasticity of the cloud to build platforms that support highly scalable applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book can help you understand all the information about building cloud-native architectures with Python in one go. In this book, we first introduce you to cloud-native architectures and how they can help you solve various problems. Then you will learn how to build microservices using REST APIs and Python, construct the web layer in an event-driven manner. Next, you will learn how to interact with data services and build web views using React. After that, we will delve into application security and performance. Then, you will also learn how to containerize your services with Docker. Finally, you will learn how to deploy your applications on AWS and Azure platforms. After deploying your application, we will conclude this book with a series of concepts and techniques around application troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-covered-in-this-book&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Covered in This Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: Introduction to cloud-native architectures and microservices, discussing the basic concepts of cloud-native architecture and setting up the application development environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2: Building microservices with Python, building your own microservices knowledge base and extending it based on your use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3: Building web applications with Python, building an initial web application and integrating it with microservices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4: Interacting with data services, teaching you how to migrate applications to different database services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5: Building web views using React.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6: Creating scalable UI with Flux, helping you understand how to create scalable applications using Flux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7: Event sourcing and CQRS, discussing how to store transactions in event form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8: Securing web applications, keeping your applications safe from external threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9: Continuous delivery, knowledge related to frequent releases of applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10: Dockerizing your services, discussing container services and running applications in Docker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11: Deploying applications to AWS platform, teaching you how to build infrastructure on AWS and establish the production environment of applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12: Deploying applications to Azure platform, discussing how to build infrastructure on Azure and establish the production environment of applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13: Monitoring cloud applications, understanding different monitoring tools for infrastructure and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-and-environment-required-to-use-this-book&#34;&gt;Tools and Environment Required to Use This Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to have Python installed on your system. A text editor, preferably Vim, Sublime, or Notepad++. In one chapter, you will need to download POSTMAN, a powerful API testing suite that can be installed as a Chrome extension. You can download it &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/postman/fhbjgbiflinjbdggehcddcbncdddomop?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it would be better if you have accounts on the following websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience&#34;&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is suitable for developers with basic Python knowledge, familiarity with the command line, and the basic principles of HTTP-based applications. It&amp;rsquo;s an ideal choice for those who want to understand how to build, test, and scale Python-based applications. No prior experience with building microservices using Python is required.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Go</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Go,&amp;rdquo; authored by Kevin Hoffman, translated by Song Jingchao, Wu Yingsong, Xu Bei, and Ma Chao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/cloud-native-go_hu53442bc8a5df1347cc048c02a27fccf1_98418_610x800_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/cloud-native-go.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/cloud-native-go/cloud-native-go.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;610&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cover of the book Cloud Native Go&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of the book Cloud Native Go&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Kevin Hoffman &amp;amp; Dan Nemeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translators: Song Jingchao, Wu Yingsong, Xu Bei, Ma Chao&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publisher: Publishing House of Electronics Industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Name: Cloud Native Go - A Guide to Building Web Cloud-Native Applications with Go and React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has been published by the Publishing House of Electronics Industry and is available for purchase &lt;a href=&#34;https://item.m.jd.com/product/12123347.html&#34; title=&#34;on JD.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on JD.com&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/jimmy-song-with-kevein-hoffman_hu312225a5a873c48f1fe96765783fcf0e_149816_1200x737_resize_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/cloud-native-go/jimmy-song-with-kevein-hoffman.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/cloud-native-go/jimmy-song-with-kevein-hoffman.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;1200&#34; data-height=&#34;737&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jimmy Song with Kevin Hoffman&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jimmy Song with Kevin Hoffman&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo taken on September 12, 2017, in Beijing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native Go shows developers how to build large-scale cloud applications that can dynamically scale to handle almost any volume of data, traffic, or users while meeting the strong demands of today&amp;rsquo;s customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Hoffman and Dan Nemeth detail modern cloud-native applications, elucidating the factors, rules, and habits associated with rapid and reliable cloud-native development. They also introduce Go, a &amp;ldquo;simple and elegant&amp;rdquo; high-performance language particularly suited for cloud development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this book, you&amp;rsquo;ll create microservices using Go, add frontend web components using ReactJS and Flux, and master advanced cloud-native technologies based on Go. Hoffman and Nemeth demonstrate how to build continuous delivery pipelines using tools like Wercker, Docker, and Dockerhub; automatically push applications to platforms; and systematically monitor application performance in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn the &amp;ldquo;way of the cloud&amp;rdquo;: why well-developed cloud software is essentially about mindset and rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand why using the Go language is the ideal choice for cloud-native microservices development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan cloud applications that support continuous delivery and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design service ecosystems and then build them test-first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push work in progress to the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use event sourcing and CQRS patterns to respond to large-scale and high-throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure cloud-based web applications: choices to make and avoid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create responsive cloud applications using third-party messaging providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build large-scale, cloud-friendly GUIs using React and Flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor dynamic scaling, failover, and fault tolerance in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-authors&#34;&gt;About the Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Hoffman&lt;/strong&gt; has helped businesses move their applications to the cloud in a modern and multi-language manner. He began programming at the age of 10, self-studying BASIC on a reassembled Commodore VIC-20. Since then, he has been passionate about building software and has spent a lot of time learning languages, frameworks, and patterns. He has built a range of software, from remote-controlled drones and biometric security systems to ultra-low-latency financial applications and mobile apps. He fell in love with the Go language while building custom components that work with Pivotal Cloud Foundry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin is the author of the popular fantasy book series (&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2fc8iES&#34; title=&#34;The Sigilord Chronicles&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Sigilord Chronicles&lt;/a&gt;
) and eagerly anticipates combining his love of building software with his love of building fantasy worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Nemeth&lt;/strong&gt; is currently a Consulting Solution Architect at Pivotal, supporting Pivotal Cloud Foundry. He has been developing software since the days of the Commodore 64 and began coding professionally in 1995, writing CGI scripts in ANSIC for a local ISP. Since then, most of his career has been spent as an independent consultant providing solutions to industries ranging from finance to pharmaceuticals, using various languages and frameworks of the time. Dan recently adopted Go as his home and enthusiastically applies it to all his projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Dan isn&amp;rsquo;t in front of a computer, he can often be found sailing or fly-fishing near Annapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: The Way of the Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2: Getting Started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3: Getting to Know Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4: Continuous Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5: Building Microservices in Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6: Leveraging Backend Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7: Building Data Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8: Event Sourcing and CQRS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9: Building Web Applications with Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10: Cloud Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 11: Using WebSockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 12: Building Web Views with React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 13: Building Scalable UIs with Flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 14: Creating a Full Application: World of FluxCraft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 15: Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix A: Troubleshooting Cloud Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
