<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song&#39;s Cloud Native Blog – Istio Weekly</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/istio-weekly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Istio Weekly on Jimmy Song&#39;s Cloud Native Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 12:27:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/istio-weekly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio Community Weekly 02</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 12:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week&amp;rsquo;s edition of the Istio Community Weekly Report! As we approach the year&amp;rsquo;s end, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share some updates and insights in the Istio community. From monthly community meetings to pro tips on using Istio effectively, this report is packed with valuable information for everyone, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned Istio user or just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-updates&#34;&gt;Community Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;join-the-monthly-istio-community-meetings&#34;&gt;Join the Monthly Istio Community Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be part of the Istio monthly community meetings to engage and connect with other enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt;: Every fourth Thursday of the month, 10 AM US/Pacific. &lt;a href=&#34;https://time.is/compare/1000_in_San_Francisco,_California&#34; title=&#34;Check your local time&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check your local time&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stay-connected&#34;&gt;Stay Connected&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calendar Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Automatically add meetings to your calendar by joining &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/istio-community-video-meetings&#34; title=&#34;this group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this group&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting Details&lt;/strong&gt;: Find agendas and notes in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/istiocommunitymeet&#34; title=&#34;working document&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;working document&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded Sessions&lt;/strong&gt;: Missed a meeting? Catch up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-zVlo1F3mUbExQ96fABWcQ&#34; title=&#34;YouTube&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;present-at-the-meeting&#34;&gt;Present at the Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your insights! Submit your talk abstract to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:istio-steering@googlegroups.com&#34; title=&#34;istio-steering@googlegroups.com&#34;&gt;istio-steering@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;
. Presentation guidelines and more details can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/istiocommunitymeet&#34; title=&#34;here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/community/tree/master?tab=readme-ov-file#community-meeting&#34; title=&#34;here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istio-pro-tips&#34;&gt;Istio Pro Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regex-in-virtualservice-routing&#34;&gt;Regex in VirtualService Routing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using regex for header-based routing in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;VirtualService&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to use Envoy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/re2/wiki/Syntax&#34; title=&#34;RE2 regex&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RE2 regex&lt;/a&gt;
 format. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match &amp;ldquo;Google&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;regex: &amp;quot;.\*Google.\*&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match &amp;ldquo;Microsoft&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;regex: &amp;quot;.\*Microsoft.\*&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;.\*&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;.\*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; pattern is essential for correct matching in Envoy. Remember, PCRE formats aren&amp;rsquo;t compatible with Istio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Point&lt;/strong&gt;: Use the RE2 regex that is compatible with Envoy for precise routing. Discussion details are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/discussions/48405&#34; title=&#34;GitHub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zero-downtime-migration-to-mutual-tls&#34;&gt;Zero Downtime Migration to Mutual TLS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagrams illustrate the zero-downtime migration process to mutual TLS and how the remote IngressGateway and Istiod establish mTLS in a primary-remote multi-cluster deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLS Migration Process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-02/tls-migration.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-02/tls-migration.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;TLS Migration Process with Zero Downtime&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;TLS Migration Process with Zero Downtime&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sequence Chart of mTLS Establishment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;sequenceDiagram
    participant IG as Ingress Gateway (Remote Cluster)
    participant K8s as Kubernetes API (Remote Cluster)
    participant SA as Service Account (Remote Cluster)
    participant Istiod as Istiod (Primary Cluster)

    Note over IG: Starts up
    IG-&gt;&gt;K8s: Request Service Account Token
    K8s-&gt;&gt;SA: Create/Retrieve Token
    SA--&gt;&gt;IG: Return Token
    Note over IG: Token Mounted in Pod

    IG-&gt;&gt;Istiod: Authenticate with Token
    Note over Istiod: Validate Token
    Istiod-&gt;&gt;Istiod: Generate mTLS Certificates
    Istiod--&gt;&gt;IG: Send mTLS Certificates

    Note over IG: Use mTLS Certificates for Secure Communication in Mesh
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/discussions/48343&#34; title=&#34;GitHub discussion&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub discussion&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the festive season approaches, we wish all members of the Istio community a very Merry Christmas! May this season bring joy, peace, and new opportunities for innovation and collaboration. Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio Community Weekly 01</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 10:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/istio-community-weekly-01/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-first-issue-of-istio-community-weekly&#34;&gt;Welcome to the First Issue of Istio Community Weekly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Istio friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to present the first issue of Istio Community Weekly. As a part of our energetic and creative community, I&amp;rsquo;ve been motivated by our collaborative spirit and the advancements in service mesh technology. This weekly series is my way of contributing back, bringing you the latest updates, discussions, and insights about Istio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week, I&amp;rsquo;ll bring you a mix of the newest developments in Istio, insightful community debates, pro tips, and important security news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all bring unique perspectives to this community, and through this weekly report, I aim to reflect our diverse viewpoints. Let&amp;rsquo;s journey together through the evolving landscape of Istio, embracing its challenges and achievements and sharing our passion for open-source innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to starting this journey with you and welcome your feedback and contributions. Let&amp;rsquo;s grow and learn together as part of the wider Istio family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading, and catch you in the next edition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-updates&#34;&gt;Community Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transition-to-github-discussions-for-istio-community-qa&#34;&gt;Transition to GitHub Discussions for Istio Community Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Istio team has announced a significant change in how community interactions and Q&amp;amp;A will be handled. The current forum at &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.istio.io/&#34; title=&#34;discuss.istio.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;discuss.istio.io&lt;/a&gt;
 is set to be archived by December 20th, and the team is transitioning to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/discussions&#34; title=&#34;GitHub Discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub Discussions&lt;/a&gt;
 for future engagements. This new platform is envisioned as a hub for users to ask questions and engage with the community. Notably, contributions in GitHub discussions will be recognized as official Istio contributions, influencing the allocation of steering contributor seats. This is a call to action for maintainers, vendors, and end users to participate actively in these discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;istio-office-hours-proposal&#34;&gt;Istio Office Hours Proposal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Istio community is introducing a new initiative: &amp;ldquo;Istio Office Hours.&amp;rdquo; This proposal aims to establish a periodic community meeting to share technical knowledge and facilitate community growth. The Office Hours are intended to help new contributors and provide a forum for current members to share insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/13voR8qZwG8lKI2_xtvYhN6msBHp0MAdvlDXMUqQGFEM/edit&#34; title=&#34;proposal document&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;proposal document&lt;/a&gt;
 for more detailed information and to participate in shaping this initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes-v129-release-shift-from-iptables-to-nftables-and-its-impact-on-istio&#34;&gt;Kubernetes v1.29 Release: Shift from iptables to nftables and Its Impact on Istio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-1.29.md&#34; title=&#34;Kubernetes v1.29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kubernetes v1.29&lt;/a&gt;
 introduces a significant shift in its networking approach. Kubernetes is now adopting nftables as an Alpha feature for the kube-proxy backend, replacing iptables. This change is due to the longstanding performance issues with iptables, which worsen with increasing rule set sizes. The development of iptables in the kernel has slowed considerably, with most activity ceasing and new features being halted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-nftables&#34;&gt;Why nftables?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nftables addresses the limitations of iptables and offers better performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major distributions like RedHat and Debian are moving away from iptables. RedHat has deprecated iptables in RHEL 9 and Debian removed it from the required packages in Debian 11 (Bullseye).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-on-istio&#34;&gt;Impact on Istio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Istio, which currently relies on iptables for traffic hijacking, might need to adapt to this change by considering the use of nftables. This shift aligns with the broader move in the Linux ecosystem towards nftables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;administrators-role&#34;&gt;Administrators&amp;rsquo; Role&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To enable this feature, administrators must use the NFTablesProxyMode feature gate and run kube-proxy with the &lt;code&gt;-proxy-mode=nftables&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There might be compatibility issues as CNI plugins, NetworkPolicy implementations, and other components that currently rely on iptables will need updates to work with nftables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change in Kubernetes v1.29 is a forward-looking step but requires careful consideration and planning for integration with systems like Istio. It’s essential for the Istio community to stay abreast of these developments and prepare for potential adjustments in future Istio versions to maintain compatibility with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-updates&#34;&gt;Project Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;istio-security-2023-005-changes-to-istio-cni-rbac-permissions&#34;&gt;ISTIO-SECURITY-2023-005: Changes to Istio CNI RBAC Permissions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-vulnerability-addressed&#34;&gt;Security Vulnerability Addressed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Istio Security Committee has identified and addressed a significant security vulnerability concerning the Istio CNI (Container Network Interface). This issue, detailed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/latest/news/security/istio-security-2023-005/&#34; title=&#34;ISTIO-SECURITY-2023-005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ISTIO-SECURITY-2023-005&lt;/a&gt;
, revolves around the potential misuse of the &lt;code&gt;istio-cni-repair-role&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;ClusterRole&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-security-risk&#34;&gt;The Security Risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a node is compromised, the existing high-level permissions of the Istio CNI could be exploited. This exploitation could escalate a local compromise to a cluster-wide security breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-taken&#34;&gt;Steps Taken&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this discovery, modifications have been made to the Istio CNI&amp;rsquo;s RBAC (Role-Based Access Control) permissions to mitigate this risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detailed information, please visit the official security advisory at &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/latest/news/security/istio-security-2023-005/&#34; title=&#34;Istio Security 2023-005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Security 2023-005&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-minor-releases&#34;&gt;New Minor Releases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Istio has released new minor patch versions to enhance security and functionality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Istio 1.18.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Istio 1.19.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Istio 1.20.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These updates include various improvements and fixes, reflecting the ongoing commitment to maintaining and enhancing the Istio service mesh&amp;rsquo;s security and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on these releases, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/latest/news/&#34; title=&#34;Istio&amp;amp;rsquo;s latest news&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio&amp;rsquo;s latest news&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hot-topics-and-discussions&#34;&gt;Hot Topics and Discussions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;debate-on-ambient-mode-transition-to-beta-in-istio-121&#34;&gt;Debate on Ambient Mode Transition to Beta in Istio 1.21&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A heated discussion unfolded in the recent combined working group meeting regarding the progression of Ambient mode to Beta in the upcoming Istio 1.21 release (Q124).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;diverging-views&#34;&gt;Diverging Views&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Solo&amp;rsquo;s Stance: Advocated for delaying the 1.21 release to ensure that Ambient mode reaches Beta status within this version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Everyone Else&amp;rsquo;s Argument: Opposed the delay, emphasizing that Ambient mode is not yet ready for Beta release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;current-outlook&#34;&gt;Current Outlook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consensus leans towards maintaining the 1.21 release schedule without including Ambient mode in Beta. The predominant view is that the Ambient mode requires further development and is unlikely to achieve Beta status in the 1.21 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discussion reflects the ongoing commitment to quality and readiness in Istio&amp;rsquo;s development process. The decision not to rush Ambient mode into Beta underscores the community&amp;rsquo;s dedication to ensuring stability and reliability in each release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istio-pro-tips&#34;&gt;Istio Pro Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;determining-the-upstream-ip-address-of-an-ingress-gateway&#34;&gt;Determining the Upstream IP Address of an Ingress Gateway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying the upstream source workload is crucial when dealing with an NLB (Network Load Balancer) before the ingress gateway, particularly for TLS offloading. In cases where the &lt;code&gt;source_workload&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;istio_requests_total&lt;/code&gt; is an ingress gateway, the real source workload needs to be discerned. A practical approach is to utilize HTTP headers for this purpose. XFF (X-Forwarded-For) is a standard method outlined in &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/latest/docs/ops/configuration/traffic-management/network-topologies/&#34; title=&#34;Istio&amp;amp;rsquo;s documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio&amp;rsquo;s documentation&lt;/a&gt;
, but custom solutions can also be implemented by adding a header through a virtual service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;envoy-version-in-istio-releases&#34;&gt;Envoy Version in Istio Releases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Istio team maintains their Envoy builds, making independent decisions about patch versions. This approach ensures faster access to necessary updates rather than waiting for official Envoy releases. Further details can be found in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/discussions/48064#discussioncomment-7794044&#34; title=&#34;GitHub discussion&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub discussion&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your feedback and participation are vital to the Istio community. If you have insights, questions, or comments, please join the discussions on GitHub and help us shape the future of Istio! Looking ahead to next week, we anticipate more exciting updates and community interactions. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
