
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – Original</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/categories/original/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Original on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Jimmy Song</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Jimmy Song</webMaster>
    
      <follow_challenge>
        <feedId>61582075856402432</feedId>
        <userId>59800919738273792</userId>
      </follow_challenge>
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/categories/original/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
                                                         
    
                                                   
                           
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Istio: Advanced Practices in Cloud Native Service Mesh</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;achieving-open-source-in-the-name-of-community&#34;&gt;Achieving Open Source in the Name of Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2018, with the support of Ant Group, the ServiceMesher community was established. Subsequently, a whirlwind of service mesh swept across China, and the community-led translation work of the official Istio documentation entered a fervent stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went on, I felt the lack of comprehensive Chinese materials introducing Istio. Therefore, in September 2018, I began conceptualizing a book about Istio and initiated the open-source e-book project &amp;ldquo;Istio Handbook&amp;rdquo; on GitHub. Several months later, with the promotion of service mesh technology and the expansion of the ServiceMesher community, I met many friends who were also passionate about Istio and service mesh technology through online and offline activities in the community. We unanimously decided to write an open-source e-book about Istio together, compiling valuable articles and experiences accumulated by the community into a systematic text to share with developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2019, under the organization of the community&amp;rsquo;s management committee, dozens of members volunteered to participate and jointly write this book. In May 2020, to better promote cloud native technology and enrich the technical content shared by the community, we established the Cloud Native Community and incorporated the original ServiceMesher community into it. The content operated by the community also expanded from service mesh technology to a more comprehensive range of cloud native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2020, the main contributors to this book formed the editorial committee, including myself, Ma Ruofei, Wang Bai Ping, Wang Wei, Luo Guangming, Zhao Huabing, Zhong Hua, and Guo Xudong. With the guidance and assistance of the publisher, we carried out subsequent version upgrades, improvements, and optimizations for this book. After repeated iterations, this book &amp;ldquo;Understanding Istio: Advanced Practices in Cloud Native Service Mesh&amp;rdquo; finally met with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover_hu_b9756916f0a1b0f6.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/istio-in-depth/cover.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;1200&#34; data-height=&#34;1569&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Book cover&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Book cover&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-book&#34;&gt;About This Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After version 1.5, Istio underwent significant architectural changes and introduced or improved multiple features, such as introducing intelligent DNS proxy, new resource objects, and improving support for virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is based on the new versions of Istio and strives to provide readers with the latest and most comprehensive content while continuously tracking the latest trends in the Istio community. Additionally, many authors of this book are frontline developers or operation engineers with rich practical experience in Istio, providing valuable reference cases for this book.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native,&amp;rdquo; authored by Zhang Liang, Wu Sheng, Ao Xiao Jian, and Song Jingchao, published by Publishing House of Electronics Industry in April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          
          &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture_hu_194c3e509aba19d8.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;
           &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/book/future-architecture/future-architecture.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;610&#34; data-height=&#34;800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cover of the book Future Architecture&#34;&gt;
          &lt;/picture&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of the book Future Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first author of this book is Zhang Liang, currently working at JD Finance. To enrich the content of the book, Zhang Liang invited his friends in the industry, Wu Sheng, Ao Xiao Jian, and myself, to co-author this ambitious work on &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture.&amp;rdquo; Below is an excerpt of his introduction to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origin-of-the-book&#34;&gt;Origin of the Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As professionals in the internet industry, we have always been at the forefront of change, constantly chasing the waves of technological advancement to avoid falling behind the pace of the times. Especially in recent years, internet architecture has undergone continuous evolution, transitioning from centralized architecture to distributed architecture, and then to cloud-native architecture. Cloud-native architecture has gradually become the protagonist of this era because it can address issues such as slow application upgrades, bloated architectures, and inability to iterate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of this wave of change, I watched as it altered the course of internet architecture and brought new ideas and developments to more and more companies and individuals. I embarked on a journey to learn and understand it, integrating it into my knowledge system to update the architectural map in my mind with the experiences and insights accumulated over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 and 2018, I experienced these changes firsthand, making projects like Elastic-Job and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/shardingsphere&#34; title=&#34;Sharding-Sphere&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sharding-Sphere&lt;/a&gt; widely recognized in the industry, internationalizing the open-source projects I was responsible for, and meeting more mentors and friends. These experiences inspired me to put what I heard, saw, knew, and felt onto paper, connecting them into this book: &amp;ldquo;Future Architecture: From Service-Oriented to Cloud-Native.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book covers everything you want to know about distributed systems, service-oriented architecture, service mesh, containers, orchestration, cloud-native, and cloud databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It contains my well-considered insights and experiences accumulated over the years, as well as my struggles of abandoning and picking up the pen again because I feel responsible for the content of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also features chapters contributed by seasoned experts in the field, including Wu Sheng, the founder of Apache Incubator project SkyWalking and an APM expert; Song Jingchao, a CNCF Ambassador, cloud-native evangelist, and founder of the Cloud-Native Community; and Ao Xiao Jian, a service mesh evangelist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: Cloud-Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2: Remote Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3: Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4: Service Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5: Observing Distributed Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6: Intrusive Service Governance Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7: Kubernetes: The Cornerstone of Cloud-Native Ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 8: Cross-Language Service Governance Solutions: Service Mesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 9: Cloud-Native Data Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 10: Distributed Database Middleware Ecosystem: ShardingSphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wings-of-aspiration&#34;&gt;Wings of Aspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The back cover of the book features the Holy Trinity statue standing in front of Old Trafford Stadium, chosen by Professor Zhang Liang as the background image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 6, 1958, while returning from Yugoslavia after securing a spot in the European Cup semi-finals, the Manchester United team encountered the Munich air disaster, disappearing in the night sky. To revive Manchester United, surviving manager Matt Busby rebuilt the team with blood, tears, and sweat. Exactly 10 years after the Munich air disaster, on May 29, 1968, Busby led his new team to finally lift the European Cup, comforting the souls of those who had passed away! The Holy Trinity statue became an eternal memorial!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faith, resilience, perseverance, miracles, and rebirth&amp;hellip; These are the strengths I feel from this sculpture. Everyone will experience peaks and valleys, see mountains and deserts in their lifetime, and I hope this book not only brings practical knowledge of internet architecture but also embodies my blessings to you all: I hope that amidst the relentless struggles on this long journey, you can have your own faith and hope, and even after traversing countless deserts and oceans, you can see the light after experiencing numerous trials!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
