
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – Istio Registry Sync</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/istio-registry-sync/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Istio Registry Sync on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Jimmy Song</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Jimmy Song</webMaster>
    
      <follow_challenge>
        <feedId>61582075856402432</feedId>
        <userId>59800919738273792</userId>
      </follow_challenge>
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:14:40 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/istio-registry-sync/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
                                                         
    
                                                   
                           
    <item>
      <title>How to Integrating Third-Party Service Registries with Istio?</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:14:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Istio relies on Kubernetes for service discovery, which generally means that microservices must be deployed within a Kubernetes cluster and use Kubernetes service discovery. However, many existing microservice projects still utilize third-party service registries like Consul and Eureka. This article will explore how to integrate these existing service registries with Istio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-for-non-kubernetes-services-in-istio&#34;&gt;Support for Non-Kubernetes Services in Istio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, Istio supported only Kubernetes services, but over time, to accommodate a broader range of application scenarios, it began supporting third-party service registries like Consul. By introducing the Mesh Configuration Protocol (MCP), Istio was able to communicate with various service discovery backends, such as Consul, thereby managing services in non-Kubernetes environments. With the introduction of the ServiceEntry resource in version 1.1, users were able to manually add external services to Istio&amp;rsquo;s service registry. By version 1.8, direct support for Consul was removed in favor of a more flexible approach through &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/latest/docs/reference/config/networking/service-entry/&#34; title=&#34;ServiceEntry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceEntry&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the integration and management of all services, whether hosted on Kubernetes or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;high-level-architecture-of-istio-proxy-configuration&#34;&gt;High-Level Architecture of Istio Proxy Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagram illustrates the high-level architecture of Istio proxy configuration, showing how configurations are ingested, transformed, and ultimately served to the Envoy proxies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/f02f7fa551ceb4c4b9fd0419b69ca6f4.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/f02f7fa551ceb4c4b9fd0419b69ca6f4.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Istio Proxy Configuration High-Level Architecture&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Istio Proxy Configuration High-Level Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;detailed-process-of-configuration-ingestion&#34;&gt;Detailed Process of Configuration Ingestion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuration Storage&lt;/strong&gt;: Responsible for reading various types of resources and aggregating them. Includes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XDS Client&lt;/strong&gt;: Reads resources via the xDS protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CRD Client&lt;/strong&gt;: Reads resources from Kubernetes Custom Resource Definitions (CRDs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filesystem Client&lt;/strong&gt;: Reads resources from the filesystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;: Aggregates service-oriented internal resources. Components used include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kube Controller&lt;/strong&gt;: Operates based on core Kubernetes types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ServiceEntry Controller&lt;/strong&gt;: Operates based on Istio types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuration-translation-and-service&#34;&gt;Configuration Translation and Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After aggregating configurations from Configuration Storage and Service Discovery, the &lt;strong&gt;Configuration Translator&lt;/strong&gt; translates them into a format suitable for the proxies, which are then served by the &lt;strong&gt;XDS Server&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the final step in applying dynamic configurations to the proxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synchronization-of-third-party-registries&#34;&gt;Synchronization of Third-Party Registries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To integrate third-party service registries, we can implement an Operator that monitors third-party service registries and pushes services in the form of ServiceEntry and WorkloadEntry resources to the Kubernetes API server. The following flowchart illustrates this synchronization process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
    
      
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/094c8461ff42db96a7c04d7a1b92b0d2.svg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/blog/how-to-integrate-third-party-registry-with-istio/094c8461ff42db96a7c04d7a1b92b0d2.svg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Synchronization of Third-Party Registries Flowchart&#34;&gt;
        
      
    
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Synchronization of Third-Party Registries Flowchart&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-for-synchronization-of-third-party-service-registries&#34;&gt;Steps for Synchronization of Third-Party Service Registries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Operator initiates a service query to the Third-Party Service Registry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Third-Party Service Registry returns the current registered service data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Operator transforms the service data into Istio&amp;rsquo;s ServiceEntry objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Operator pushes the transformed ServiceEntry to the Kubernetes API Server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kubernetes API Server notifies Istiod of the changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Istiod updates the configurations of the Envoy Proxies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Operator regularly checks the Third-Party Service Registry to monitor service changes, updating the ServiceEntry and re-pushing it to the Kubernetes API Server upon detection of changes, thus completing the service synchronization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istio-registry-sync&#34;&gt;Istio Registry Sync&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed by Tetrate, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.tetrate.io/istio-subscription/integrations/registry-sync/introduction&#34; title=&#34;Istio Registry Sync&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Registry Sync&lt;/a&gt; is an extension operator that can run as an add-on for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.tetrate.io/istio-subscription/&#34; title=&#34;TIS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TIS&lt;/a&gt;. It supports the integration of non-Kubernetes service registries (such as AWS Cloud Map and Consul) with Istio. This tool provides several use cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid Application Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: In hybrid environments, traditional applications using Consul and microservices in AWS using Cloud Map can achieve seamless service discovery through Istio Registry Sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Endpoint Management&lt;/strong&gt;: In environments where services frequently scale, Istio Registry Sync quickly reflects changes from the configured registry, ensuring accurate traffic management strategies within Istio&amp;rsquo;s service mesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified Monitoring and Security Posture&lt;/strong&gt;: By integrating services from all environments into Istio, it leverages service health metrics and a unified security protocol, such as mTLS, to ensure encrypted and authenticated communication across all services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the methods described above, you can effectively integrate Istio with third-party service registries, whether by developing a custom Operator or using the ready-made Istio Registry Sync tool. This not only maintains the modernization of services but also ensures efficient collaboration across different environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/blob/master/pilot/doc/architecture.md&#34; title=&#34;Istio Pilot Architecture - github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Pilot Architecture - github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.tetrate.io/istio-subscription/integrations/registry-sync/introduction&#34; title=&#34;Istio Registry Sync Documentation - docs.tetrate.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Registry Sync Documentation - docs.tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was initially published at &lt;a href=&#34;LINK&#34; title=&#34;tetrate.io&#34;&gt;tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
