<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song&#39;s Cloud Native Blog – Notice</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notice on Jimmy Song&#39;s Cloud Native Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:27:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>See you in KubeCon Paris!</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/kubecon-eu-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/kubecon-eu-2024/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce that I will be attending this year&amp;rsquo;s KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon event, and it will be my first time having the opportunity to attend KubeCon in Europe. I am greatly looking forward to meeting everyone in Paris and sharing insights and experiences about cloud-native technologies. In addition to participating in the main event, I will also be attending &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/co-located-events/istio-day/&#34; title=&#34;Istio Day&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Day&lt;/a&gt;
 and will be available at Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s booth (J14) to meet with everyone. I hope to spend this exciting time with you all and welcome you to come and chat with me!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement of Cloud Native Library</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-public-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 08:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-public-library/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;See the cloud native public library at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lib.jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;https://lib.jimmysong.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://lib.jimmysong.io/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cloud native public library project is a documentation project built using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com&#34; title=&#34;Wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt;
 theme, open sourced on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloud-native-library&#34; title=&#34;GitHub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also adjusted the home page, menu and directory structure of the site, and the books section of the site will be maintained using the new theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-native-library-positioning&#34;&gt;Cloud native library positioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cloud native public library is a collection of cloud native related books and materials published and translated by the author since 2017, and is a compendium and supplement to the dozen or so books already published. The original materials will continue to be published in the form of GitBooks, and the essence and related content will be sorted into the cloud native public library through this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the events section of this site has been revamped and moved to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/event/&#34; title=&#34;new page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;new page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enterprise Service Mesh company Tetrate is hiring</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/tetrate-recruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 07:28:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/tetrate-recruit/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Join a team of world-class engineers working on the next generation of networking services using Istio, Envoy, Apache SkyWalking and a few of the open projects to define the next generation of cloud native network service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istio-upstream-contributor-golang&#34;&gt;Istio upstream contributor: Golang&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for engineers with strong distributed systems experience to join our team. We are building a secure, robust, and highly available service mesh platform for mission critical enterprise applications spanning both legacy and modern infrastructure. This is an opportunity to dedicate a significant amount of contribution to Istio upstream on a regular basis. If you are a fan of Istio and would like to increase your contribution on a dedicated basis, this would be an opportunity for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamentals-based problem solving skills; Drive decision by function, first principles based mindset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate bias-to-action and avoid analysis-paralysis; Drive action to the finish line and on time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are ego-less when searching for the best ideasIntellectually curious with a penchant for seeing opportunities in ambiguity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understands the difference between attention to detail vs. detailed - oriented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values autonomy and results over process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You contribute effectively outside of your specialty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience building distributed system platforms using Golang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Kubernetes, service mesh technologies such as Istio and Envoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent understanding of networking protocols, concepts, consistency properties of distributed systems, techniques to identify and reconcile configuration drifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience contributing to open source projects is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with WebAssembly is a plus. Familiarity with Golang, hardware/software load balancers (F5, NGINX), HSM modules, Active Directory/LDAP is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage written and asynchronous communication in English, and proficient oral English is not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-systems-engineer-enterprise-infrastructure-data-plane-golang-or-c-developers&#34;&gt;Distributed Systems Engineer, Enterprise Infrastructure (Data plane) GoLang or C++ Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking backend software engineers experienced in building distributed systems using Golang and gRPC. We are building a secure, and highly available service mesh platform for mission-critical enterprise applications for Fortune 500 companies, spanning both the legacy and modern infrastructure. Should possess strong fundamentals in distributed systems and networking. Familiarity with technologies like Kubernetes, Istio, and Envoy, as well as open contributions would be a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience building distributed system platforms using C++, Golang, and gRPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Kubernetes, service mesh technologies such as Istio and Envoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent understanding of networking protocols, concepts, consistency properties of distributed systems, techniques to identify and reconcile configuration drifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience contributing to open source projects is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with the following is a plus: WebAssembly, Authorization: NGAC, RBAC, ABAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with hardware/software load balancers (F5, NGINX), HSM modules, Active Directory/LDAP is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;site-reliability-engineer-sre&#34;&gt;Site Reliability Engineer, SRE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) combines software and systems engineering to build and run scalable, massively distributed, fault-tolerant systems. As part of the team, you will be working on ensuring that Tetrate’s platform has reliability/uptime appropriate to users’ needs as well as a fast rate of improvement. Additionally, much of our engineering effort focuses on building infrastructure, improving the platform troubleshooting abilities, and eliminating toil through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematic problem-solving approach, coupled with excellent communication skills and a sense of ownership/finish and self-directed drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong fundamentals in operating, debugging, and troubleshooting distributed systems(stateful and/or stateless) and networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Kubernetes, service mesh technologies such as Istio and EnvoyAbility to debug, optimize code, and automate routine tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience programming in at least one of the following languages: C++, Rust, Python, Go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with the concepts of quantifying failure and availability in a prescriptive manner using SLOs and SLIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in performance analysis and tuning is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worldwide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are remote with presence in China, Indonesia, India, Japan, U.S., Canada, Ireland, the Netherlands, Spain, and Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send GitHub or online links that showcase your code style along with your resume to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:careers@tetrate.io&#34; title=&#34;careers@tetrate.io&#34;&gt;careers@tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-tetrate&#34;&gt;About Tetrate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by Envoy and Istio, its ﬂagship product, Tetrate Service Bridge, enables bridging traditional and modern workloads. Customers can get consistent baked-in observability, runtime security and traffic management for all their workloads, in any environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the technology, Tetrate brings a world-class team that leads the open Envoy and Istio projects, providing best practices and playbooks that enterprises can use to modernize their people and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://loxo.co/email_tracking/click?id=9840111&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fvaruntalwar%2F&#34; title=&#34;Varun&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Varun&lt;/a&gt;
, co-founder was the initial founder of Istio and gRPC back in Google. We are a two-year-old start-up building compelling network products and services that we believe will result in a step function change in the industry. &lt;a href=&#34;https://loxo.co/email_tracking/click?id=9840111&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fpragashjj%2F&#34; title=&#34;JJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JJ&lt;/a&gt;
, co-founder, started the cloud infrastructure team (working alongside Mesos, VM, OS and Provisioning infrastructure teams &amp;ndash; under platform team) at Twitter. What got him excited to leave Twitter to start this company is the ability to create a change in how service development happens in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tetrate was founded in Silicon Valley with a large number of our team represented in Canada,, China, India, Indonesia, Ireland, Japan, New Zealand, Singapore, Spain, the Netherlands and Ukraine. Our recruiting goal is simple: find the best talent no matter the background and location. We don’t recruit to a title or a role, instead, we focus on problems that need to be solved. It would be great to discuss overlaps and interests over a live call. You choose where you want to work, flexible time away and work schedule. We have teams get-togethers about 3-4 times a year, most recently in SF, Seattle, Barcelona, San Diego, Washington D.C. and Bandung. This helps with building rapport which then helps with collaboration when you are working virtually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, pleases visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://tetrate.io&#34; title=&#34;tetrate.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetrate Academy Releases Free Istio Fundamentals Course</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/tetrate-istio-fundamental-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/tetrate-istio-fundamental-courses/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Tetrate Academy has recently released the Istio Fundamentals Course, which is now available for free. Sign up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://academy.tetrate.io/courses/istio-fundamentals&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate Academy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate Academy&lt;/a&gt;
 now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-curriculum&#34;&gt;Course curriculum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the curriculum:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Mesh and Istio Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing Istio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observability: Telemetry and Logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real World Examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are self-assessment questions at the end of each course. I have passed the course, and here is the certificate after passing the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/tetrate-istio-fundamental-courses/tetrate-istio-fundamentals-jimmysong.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/notice/tetrate-istio-fundamental-courses/tetrate-istio-fundamentals-jimmysong.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;1200&#34; data-height=&#34;847&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Tetrate Academy Istio Fundamentals Course&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tetrate Academy Istio Fundamentals Course&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;More&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Tetrate will release the Certified Istio Administrator (CIA) exam and welcome all Istio users and administrators to follow and register for it.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IstioCon 2021 Lightning Talk Preview</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istiocon-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istiocon-2021/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istiocon-2021/istio-con-jimmysong.png&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/notice/istiocon-2021/istio-con-jimmysong.png&#34; data-width=&#34;1024&#34; data-height=&#34;576&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;IstioCon 2021 poster (Jimmy Song)&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;IstioCon 2021 poster (Jimmy Song)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic: Service Mesh in China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time: February 23rd, 10:00 - 10:10 am Beijing time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to participate: &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.istio.io/istiocon-2021/&#34; title=&#34;IstioCon 2021 website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IstioCon 2021 website&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost: Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From February 22-25, Beijing time, the Istio community will be hosting the first IstioCon online, and registration is free to attend! I will be giving a lightning talk on Tuesday, February 23rd (the 12th day of the first month of the lunar calendar), as an evangelist and witness of Service Mesh technology in China, I will introduce the Service Mesh industry and community in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a member of the inaugural IstioCon organizing committee with Zhonghu Xu (Huawei) and Shaojun Ding (Intel), as well as the organizer of the China region. Considering Istio&amp;rsquo;s large audience in China, we have arranged for Chinese presentations that are friendly to the Chinese time zone. There will be a total of 14 sharing sessions in Chinese, plus dozens more in English. The presentations will be in both lightning talk (10 minutes) and presentation (40 minutes) formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the Cloud Native Community &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cloudnative.to/istio/&#34; title=&#34;Istio SIG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio SIG&lt;/a&gt;
 to participate in the networking at this conference. For the schedule of IstioCon 2021, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.istio.io/istiocon-2021/&#34; title=&#34;IstioCon 2021 official website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IstioCon 2021 official website&lt;/a&gt;
, or click for details.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ServiceMesher website is no longer maintained, the original blog has been migrated to the cloud native community</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/servicemesher-blog-merged/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/servicemesher-blog-merged/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com&#34; title=&#34;ServiceMesher website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher website&lt;/a&gt;
 has lost connection with the webhook program on the web publishing server because the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/website&#34; title=&#34;GitHub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
 where the code is hosted has has been &amp;ldquo;lost&amp;rdquo; and the hosting server is temporarily unable to log in, so the site cannot be updated. Today I spent a day migrating all the blogs on ServiceMesher to the Cloud Native Community website &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to&#34; title=&#34;cloudnative.to&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cloudnative.to&lt;/a&gt;
, and as of today, there are 354 blogs on the Cloud Native Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/servicemesher-blog-merged/servicemesher-blogs.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/notice/servicemesher-blog-merged/servicemesher-blogs.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;2542&#34; data-height=&#34;1033&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;ServiceMesher blogs&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;ServiceMesher blogs&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we plan to archive &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/&#34; title=&#34;ServiceMesher official GitHub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher official GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
 (all pages under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com&#34; title=&#34;servicemesher.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;servicemesher.com&lt;/a&gt;
 domain) We are no longer accepting new PRs, so please submit them directly to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudnativeto/cloudnative.to&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Native Community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Community&lt;/a&gt;
. Thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to Alibaba Cloud Hong Kong node</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/migrating-to-alibaba-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 21:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/migrating-to-alibaba-cloud/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Just tonight, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;jimmysong.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;jimmysong.io&lt;/a&gt;
 website was moved to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;Alibaba&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alibaba&lt;/a&gt;
 Cloud Hong Kong node. This is to further optimize the user experience and increase access speed. I purchased an ECS on the Alibaba Cloud Hong Kong node, and now I have a public IP and can set subdomains. The website was previously deployed on GitHub Pages, the access speed is average, and it has to withstand GitHub instability. Impact (In recent years, GitHub downtime has occurred).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the blog has also done a lot to improve the site, thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/baijunyao&#34; title=&#34;Bai Jun away @baijunyao&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bai Jun away @baijunyao&lt;/a&gt;
 strong support, a lot of work for the revision of the site, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the theme color scheme and deepened the contrast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use aligolia to support full site search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized mobile display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articles in the blog have added zoom function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added table of contents to blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is built on the theme of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/themefisher/educenter-hugo&#34; title=&#34;educenter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;educenter&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the majority of netizens who have supported this website for several years. The website has been in use for more than three years and has millions of visits. It has undergone two major revisions before and after, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/notice/website-revision-notice/&#34; title=&#34;on January 31, 2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on January 31, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
 and October 8, 2017, respectively. And changed the theme of the website. In the future, I will share more cloud-native content with you as always, welcome to collect, forward, and join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/&#34; title=&#34;cloud-native community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cloud-native community&lt;/a&gt;
 to communicate with the majority of cloud-native developers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Cloud Native Application</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 22:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/007S8ZIlly1gf65jqq5oog30go03vjt9.gif&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/007S8ZIlly1gf65jqq5oog30go03vjt9.gif&#34; data-width=&#34;600&#34; data-height=&#34;139&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just the other day, Java just celebrated its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infoworld.com/article/3544229/java-programming-language-celebrates-25-years.html&#34; title=&#34;25th birthday&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;25th birthday&lt;/a&gt;
, and from the time of its birth it was called &amp;ldquo;write once, run everywhere&amp;rdquo;, but more than 20 years later, there is still a deep gap between programming and actual production delivery. the world of IT is never short of concepts, and if a concept doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem, then it&amp;rsquo;s time for another layer of concepts. it&amp;rsquo;s been 6 years since Kubernetes was born, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for the post-Kubernetes era - the era of cloud-native applications!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/007S8ZIlly1gf65wnt4v1j31x40jmjtz.jpg&#34; data-img=&#34;/en/notice/guide-to-cloud-native-app/007S8ZIlly1gf65wnt4v1j31x40jmjtz.jpg&#34; data-width=&#34;2488&#34; data-height=&#34;706&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cloud Native Stage&#34;&gt;
    
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cloud Native Stage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This white paper will take you on a journey to explore the development path of cloud-native applications in the post-Kubernetes era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of the ideas conveyed include.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-native has passed through a savage growth period and is moving towards uniform application of standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; native language does not fully describe the cloud-native application architecture, and the development and operation functions are heavily coupled in the configuration of resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator&amp;rsquo;s expansion of the Kubernetes ecosystem has led to the fragmentation of cloud-native applications, and there is an urgent need for a unified application definition standard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The essence of OAM is to separate the R&amp;amp;D and O&amp;amp;M concerns in the definition of cloud-native applications, and to further abstract resource objects, simplify and encompass everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kubernetes Next Generation&amp;rdquo; refers to the fact that after Kubernetes became the infrastructure layer standard, the focus of the cloud-native ecology is being overtaken by the application layer, and the last two years have been a powerful exploration of the hot Service Mesh process, and the era of cloud-native application architecture based on Kubernetes is coming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes has become an established operating platform for cloud-native applications, and this white paper will expand with Kubernetes as the default platform, including an explanation of the OAM-based hierarchical model for cloud-native applications.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishment of the Cloud Native Community</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-community-announecement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-community-announecement/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2020, due to the outbreak of the Crona-19 pandemic, employees around the world began to work at home. Though the distance between people grew farer, there was a group of people, who were us working in the cloud native area, gathered together for a common vision. During the past three months, we have set up the community management committee and used our spare time working together to complete the preparatory work for the community. Today we are here to announce the establishment of the Cloud Native Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is eating the world. —— Marc Andreessen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sentence has been quoted countless times, and with the rise of Cloud Native, we’d like to talk about “Cloud Native is eating the software.” As more and more enterprises migrate their services to the cloud, the original development mode of enterprises cannot adapt to the application scenarios in the cloud, and it is being reshaped to conform to the cloud native standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is cloud native? Cloud native is a collection of best practices in architecture, r&amp;amp;d process and team culture to support faster innovation, superior user experience, stable and reliable user service and efficient r&amp;amp;d. The relationship between the open source community and the cloud native is inseparable. It is the existence of the open source community, especially the end user community, that greatly promotes the continuous evolution of cloud native technologies represented by container, service mesh and microservices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation) holds Cloud Native conference every year in the international community, which has a wide audience and great influence. But it was not held in China for the first time until 2018, after several successful international events. However, there are no independent foundations or neutral open source communities in China. In recent years, many cloud native enthusiasts in China have set up many communication groups and held many meetups, which are very popular. Many excellent open source projects have emerged in the cloud native field, but there is no organized neutral community for overall management. Under this background, the Cloud Native Community emerges at the right moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Native Community is an open source community with technology, temperature and passion. It was founded spontaneously by a group of industry elites who love open source and uphold the principle of  consensus, co-governance, co-construction and sharing. The aim of the community is: connection, neutral, open source. We are based in China, facing the world, enterprise neutrality, focusing on open source, and giving feedback to open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction for the Steering Community:&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/en/team/&#34; title=&#34;https://cloudnative.to/en/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cloudnative.to/en/team/&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will gain the followings after joining the community:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge and news closer to the source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A more valuable network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More professional and characteristic consultation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunities to get closer to opinion leaders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster and more efficient personal growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More knowledge sharing and exposure opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More industry talent to be found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@cloudnative.to&#34; title=&#34;mailto:contact@cloudnative.to&#34;&gt;mailto:contact@cloudnative.to&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CloudNativeTo&#34; title=&#34;https://twitter.com/CloudNativeTo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/CloudNativeTo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jimmysong.io website revision notice</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/website-revision-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 12:27:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/website-revision-notice/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;2020 is indeed a bad start. In less than a month, I hardly heard any good news:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump assassinated Major General Sulaymani of Iran; this pneumonia outbreak in Wuhan; the news that my basketball icon Kobe died of a helicopter crash really shocked me, and the Lakers said goodbye on the 24th. This gave me another spiritual blow during the Spring Festival, which was originally lacking in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 is bound to be a year deeply remembered in all humankind. In the last few days of the first month of the year, I decided to revise the website. The first reason was that I could n’t go out during the extended Chinese New Year holiday, and it was boring at home. And many pictures on the website were saved on Weibo map beds. The picture bed is unstable, causing many photos to be irretrievable; coupled with a habit of organizing the website every long holiday (the last revision of the website was completed during the National Day holiday in 2018, completed at home for 7 days), so I decided to The website has been revised again and it has become what it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website has the following features after this revision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reorganize the website content, the structure is more reasonable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support email subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images are stored on Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive static website, card design, better user experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is welcome to enter your email address in the email input box at the bottom of the page. Once there is an important content update on this site, we will push you through the email as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese version of Google Engineering Practice Documents</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/google-engineering-practices-zh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 10:23:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/google-engineering-practices-zh/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A few days ago during the Mid-Autumn Festival, I translated &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices&#34; title=&#34;Google&amp;amp;rsquo;s Engineering Practices documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Engineering Practices documentation&lt;/a&gt;
 , which is open source on Github. The original document Github address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/google/eng-practices&lt;/a&gt;
 , the main content so far is summarized by Google How to conduct a &lt;strong&gt;Code Review&lt;/strong&gt; guide, based on the title of the original Github repository, we will add more Google engineering practices in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github:&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/eng-practices&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/eng-practices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rootsongjc/eng-practices&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse online: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/eng-practices&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/eng-practices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/eng-practices&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The translation uses the same style and directory structure as the original document. In fact, if the original text has international requirements, it can be directly incorporated, but according to the translation suggestions submitted by several previous people, the author of this project does not recommend translation. The first is translation. The documents may be unmaintained, and the accuracy of the documents cannot be guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For suggestions on Chinese integration, see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices/pull/12&#34; title=&#34;Add Chinese translation #12&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Add Chinese translation #12&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/eng-practices/pull/8&#34; title=&#34;Add the link of Chinese version of code reviewer’s guide #8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Add the link of Chinese version of code reviewer’s guide #8&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio 1.1 released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 23:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The following paragraph is a release note from the Istio official blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/blog/2019/announcing-1.1/&#34; title=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/blog/2019/announcing-1.1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://istio.io/zh/blog/2019/announcing-1.1/&lt;/a&gt;
 , which I translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Istio was released at 4 a.m. Beijing time today and 1 p.m. Pacific time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 1.0 release last July, we have done a lot to help people get Istio into production. We expected to release a lot of patches (six patches have been released so far!), But we are also working hard to add new features to the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme for version 1.1 is &amp;ldquo;Enterprise Ready&amp;rdquo;. We are happy to see more and more companies using Istio in production, but as some big companies join in, Istio also encounters some bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main areas we focus on include performance and scalability. As people gradually put Istio into production and use larger clusters to run more services with higher capacity, there may be some scaling and performance issues. Sidecar takes up too much resources and adds too much latency. The control plane (especially Pilot) consumes excessive resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put a lot of effort into making the data plane and control plane more efficient. In the 1.1 performance test, we observed that sidecars typically require 0.5 vCPU to process 1000 rps. A single Pilot instance can handle 1000 services (and 2000 pods) and consumes 1.5 vCPUs and 2GB of memory. Sidecar adds 5 milliseconds at the 50th percentile and 10 milliseconds at the 99th percentile (the execution strategy will increase latency).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also completed the work of namespace isolation. You can use the Kubernetes namespace to enforce control boundaries to ensure that teams do not interfere with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also improved multi-cluster functionality and usability. We listened to the community and improved the default settings for flow control and policies. We introduced a new component called Galley. Galley validates YAML configuration, reducing the possibility of configuration errors. Galley is also used in multi-cluster setups-collecting service discovery information from each Kubernetes cluster. We also support other multi-cluster topologies, including single control planes and multiple synchronous control planes, without the need for flat network support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/about/notes/1.1/&#34; title=&#34;release notes for&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release notes for&lt;/a&gt;
 more information and details .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more progress on this project. As we all know, Istio has many moving parts, and they take on too much work. To address this, we have recently established the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/community/blob/master/WORKING-GROUPS.md#working-group-meetings&#34; title=&#34;Usability Working Group (available&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Usability Working Group (available&lt;/a&gt;
 at any time). A lot happened in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/community#community-meeting&#34; title=&#34;community meeting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;community meeting&lt;/a&gt;
 (Thursday at 11 am) and in the working group. You can log in to &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.istio.io/&#34; title=&#34;discuss.istio.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;discuss.istio.io&lt;/a&gt;
 with GitHub credentials to participate in the discussion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has contributed to Istio over the past few months-patching 1.0, adding features to 1.1, and extensive testing recently on 1.1. Special thanks to companies and users who work with us to install and upgrade to earlier versions to help us identify issues before they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, go to the latest documentation and install version 1.1! Happy meshing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;official-website&#34;&gt;Official website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ServiceMesher community has been maintaining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34; title=&#34;Chinese page of the&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chinese page of the&lt;/a&gt;
 official Istio documentation since the 0.6 release of Istio . As of March 19, 2019, there have been 596 PR merges, and more than 310 documents have been maintained. Thank you for your efforts! Some documents may lag slightly behind the English version. The synchronization work is ongoing. For participation, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-official-translation&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-official-translation.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-official-translation.&lt;/a&gt;
 Istio official website has a language switch button on the right side of each page. You can always Switch between Chinese and English versions, you can also submit document modifications, report website bugs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ServiceMesher Community Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ServiceMesher community website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.servicemesher.com&lt;/a&gt;
 covers all technical articles in the Service Mesh field and releases the latest activities in a timely manner. It is your one-stop portal to learn about Service Mesh and participate in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate Istio Handbook to the ServiceMesher community</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-handbook-by-servicemesher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 16:55:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-handbook-by-servicemesher/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Istio handbook was originally an open source e-book I created (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/istio-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/istio-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt;
 ). It has been written for 8 months before donating to the ServiceMesher community. In order to further popularize Istio and Service Mesh technology, this book Donate to the community for co-authoring. The content of the original book was migrated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt;
 on March 10, 2019. The original book will no longer be updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading address online: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/istio-handbook/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/istio-handbook/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.servicemesher.com/istio-handbook/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceptual picture of this book, cover photo of &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysongio.tuchong.com/24318231/&#34; title=&#34;Shanghai Jing&amp;amp;rsquo;an Temple at night&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shanghai Jing&amp;rsquo;an Temple at night&lt;/a&gt;
 , photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;Jimmy Song&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The publishing copyright of this book belongs to the blog post of Electronic Industry Press. Please do not print and distribute it without authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34; title=&#34;Istio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt;
 is a service mesh framework jointly developed by Google, IBM, Lyft, etc., and began to enter the public vision in early 2017. As an important infrastructure layer that inherits Kubernetes and connects to the serverless architecture in the cloud-native era, Istio is of crucial importance important. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;The ServiceMesher community,&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The ServiceMesher community,&lt;/a&gt;
 as one of the earliest open source communities in China that is researching and promoting Service Mesh technology, decided to integrate community resources and co-author an open source e-book for readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-book&#34;&gt;About this book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book originates from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/istio-handbook&#34; title=&#34;rootsongjc / istio-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rootsongjc / istio-handbook&lt;/a&gt;
 and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-knowledge-map&#34; title=&#34;Istio knowledge map&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio knowledge map&lt;/a&gt;
 created by the ServiceMesher community .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is based on Istio 1.0+ and includes, but is not limited to , topics in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-knowledge-map&#34; title=&#34;Istio Knowledge Graph&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Knowledge Graph&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;participate-in-the-book&#34;&gt;Participate in the book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/istio-handbook/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34; title=&#34;writing guidelines of this book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;writing guidelines of this book&lt;/a&gt;
 and join the Slack channel discussion after joining the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;ServiceMesher community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher community&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes and Istio Service Mesh Cloud Native Local Video Demo Show</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-kubernetes-service-mesh-local-demo-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 20:57:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloud-native-kubernetes-service-mesh-local-demo-show/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This video was recorded on the last day of 2018 and demonstrates the use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster&#34; title=&#34;rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster to&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster to&lt;/a&gt;
 automatically deploy a Kubernetes cluster and &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34; title=&#34;Istio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt;
 Service Mesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I mentioned that kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster released v1.2.0 version to deploy a cloud-native experimental environment with one click. Someone in the Kubernetes and Service Mesh community asked me a long time ago to make a video to explain and demonstrate how to install Kubernetes and Istio Service Mesh, because I&amp;rsquo;m always busy, I&amp;rsquo;ve always made some time. Today, I will give a demo video, just don&amp;rsquo;t watch the video for a few minutes. In order to make this video, it took me half an hour to record, two hours to edit, and many years of shooting. , Editing, containers, virtual machines, Kubernetes, service grid experience. This is not so much a farewell as a new beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the video was first &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/26kbaZxcB4A&#34; title=&#34;posted&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt;
 on &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/26kbaZxcB4A&#34; title=&#34;YouTube&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;
 , it was explained in English (just a few supplementary instructions, it does n’t matter if you do n’t understand, just read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster/blob/master/README-cn.md&#34; title=&#34;Chinese documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chinese documentation&lt;/a&gt;
 on GitHub ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/av39514214/&#34; title=&#34;Skip to bilibli to watch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Skip to bilibli to watch&lt;/a&gt;
 . If you are interested in drone aerial photography, you can also take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://space.bilibili.com/31004924&#34; title=&#34;Jimmy Song&amp;amp;rsquo;s aerial photography works&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&amp;rsquo;s aerial photography works&lt;/a&gt;
 . Please support the coin or like, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, you can send a barrage or comment below the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS. Some people will ask why you chose to use bilibli, because there are no ads for watching videos on this platform, and most of them are uploaded by the Up master. Although the two-dimensional elements are mostly, the community atmosphere is still good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more exciting videos, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://space.bilibili.com/31004924&#34; title=&#34;Jimmy Song&amp;amp;rsquo;s bibli homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jimmy Song&amp;rsquo;s bibli homepage&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubecon&amp;CloudNativeCon Seattle 2018</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/kubecon-cloudnativecon-seattle-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 15:47:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/kubecon-cloudnativecon-seattle-2018/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNative in North America is the most worthy cloud-native event every year. This time it will be held in Seattle for four days, from December 10th to 13th, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-north-america-2018/&#34; title=&#34;official website of the conference&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official website of the conference&lt;/a&gt;
 . This year, &lt;strong&gt;8,000&lt;/strong&gt; people participated. You should notice that Kubernetes has become more and more low-level. Cloud-native application developers do not need to pay much attention to it. Major companies are publishing their own cloud-native technology stack layouts, including IBM, VMware, SAP, Startups around this ecosystem are still emerging. The PPT sharing address of the local conference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/warmchang/KubeCon-North-America-2018&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/warmchang/KubeCon-North-America-2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/warmchang/KubeCon-North-America-2018&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;strong&gt;thank you William Zhang for finishing and sharing the slides of this conference&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seattle-scene&#34;&gt;Seattle scene&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janet Kuo from Google describes the path to cloud-native technology adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same event of KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon, the scene of the first EnvoyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon Seattle, various directors, directors, directors, VPs, and Gartner analysts from IBM, Google, Mastercard, VMware, and Gartner are conducting live discussions on the topic of Scaling with Service Mesh and Istio. Why do we talk about Istio when we talk about Service Mesh? What is not suitable for Istio use case. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/warmchang/KubeCon-North-America-2018&#34; title=&#34;PPT&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PPT&lt;/a&gt;
 contains basic introduction, getting started, a total of more than 200 Deep Dive as well as practical application, we recommend you according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-north-america-2018/&#34; title=&#34;the General Assembly&amp;amp;rsquo;s official website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the General Assembly&amp;rsquo;s official website&lt;/a&gt;
 to choose topics of interest to look at the schedule, otherwise I might see, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-impression&#34;&gt;A little impression&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon is held three times a year, Europe, China and North America. China is the first time this year, and it will be held in Shanghai in November. It is said that it will be held in June next year. Although everyone said that Kubernetes has become boring, the conference about Kubernetes There is still a lot of content, and the use of CRD to extend Kubernetes usage is increasing. Service Mesh has begun to become hot. As can be seen from the live pictures above, there are a large number of participants on the site and related topics are also increasing. It is known as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/blog/microservices-post-kubernetes/&#34; title=&#34;microservice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;microservice&lt;/a&gt;
 in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/blog/microservices-post-kubernetes/&#34; title=&#34;post-Kubernetes era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;post-Kubernetes era&lt;/a&gt;
 . This must be It will be an important development direction of cloud native after Kubernetes, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;ServiceMesher community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher community&lt;/a&gt;
 pays close attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Handbook v1.4 is released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/new-kubernetes-handbook-released-and-say-hello-to-post-kubernetes-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 10:23:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/new-kubernetes-handbook-released-and-say-hello-to-post-kubernetes-era/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;strong&gt;postscript&lt;/strong&gt; from the post- &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt; era. Just this evening I saw a post by Bilgin Ibryam &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infoq.com/articles/microservices-post-kubernetes&#34; title=&#34;Microservices in a Post-Kuberentes Era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microservices in a Post-Kuberentes Era&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 9, 2017, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook&#34; title=&#34;Kubernetes Handbook-Kubernetes Chinese Guide / Cloud Native Application Architecture Practice Manual&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Handbook-Kubernetes Chinese Guide / Cloud Native Application Architecture Practice Manual&lt;/a&gt;
 was first submitted. In the past 16 months, 53 contributors participated, 1,088 commits, and a total of 23,9014 Chinese characters were written. At the same time , thousands of enthusiasts have gathered in the &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes &amp;amp; Cloud Native combat group&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been more than 4 months since the previous version was released. During this period, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34; title=&#34;Kubernetes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://prometheus.io/&#34; title=&#34;Prometheus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;
 graduated from CNCF respectively and have matured commercially. These two projects have basically taken shape and will not change much in the future. Kubernetes was originally developed for container orchestration. In order to solve the problem of microservice deployment, Kubernetes has gained popularity. The current &lt;strong&gt;microservices&lt;/strong&gt; have gradually entered the &lt;strong&gt;post-Kubernetes era&lt;/strong&gt; . Service Mesh and cloud native redefine &lt;strong&gt;microservices&lt;/strong&gt; and distributed applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this version was released, the PDF size was 108M with a total of 239,014 Chinese characters. It is recommended to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/&#34; title=&#34;browse online&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;browse online&lt;/a&gt;
 , or clone the project and install the Gitbook command to compile it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version has the following improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/usecases/istio-tutorial.html&#34; title=&#34;Istio Service Mesh tutorial&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio Service Mesh tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-vagrant-centos-cluster/blob/master/README-cn.md&#34; title=&#34;use VirtualBox and Vagrant set up in a local cluster and distributed Kubernetes Istio Service Mesh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;use VirtualBox and Vagrant set up in a local cluster and distributed Kubernetes Istio Service Mesh&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added cloud native programming language &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/cloud-native/cloud-native-programming-language-ballerina.html&#34; title=&#34;Ballerina&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ballerina&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/cloud-native/cloud-native-programming-language-pulumi.html&#34; title=&#34;Pulumi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pulumi&lt;/a&gt;
 introduced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/cloud-native/cloud-native-local-quick-start.html&#34; title=&#34;Quick Start Guide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Kubernetes 1.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/usecases/the-enterprise-path-to-service-mesh-architectures.html&#34; title=&#34;enterprise-level service mesh adoption path guide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;enterprise-level service mesh adoption path guide&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/usecases/sofamesh.html&#34; title=&#34;SOFAMesh chapter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOFAMesh chapter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added vision for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/cloud-native/the-future-of-cloud-native.html&#34; title=&#34;cloud-native future&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cloud-native future&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/cloud-native/cncf-charter.html&#34; title=&#34;CNCF charter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNCF charter&lt;/a&gt;
 and participation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added notes for Docker image repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/usecases/envoy.html&#34; title=&#34;Envoy chapter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Envoy chapter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/appendix/about-kcsp.html&#34; title=&#34;KCSP (Kubernetes certification service providers)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KCSP (Kubernetes certification service providers)&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/appendix/about-cka-candidate.html&#34; title=&#34;CKA (Certified Kubernetes administrator)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CKA (Certified Kubernetes administrator)&lt;/a&gt;
 instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated some configuration files, YAML and reference links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook/concepts/cri.html&#34; title=&#34;CRI chapter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRI chapter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed obsolete description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved etcdctl command usage tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some typos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;browse-and-download&#34;&gt;Browse and download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse online &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/kubernetes-handbook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To make it easy for everyone to download, I put a copy on &lt;a href=&#34;https://share.weiyun.com/5YbhTIG&#34; title=&#34;Weiyun&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weiyun&lt;/a&gt;
 , which is available in PDF (108MB), MOBI (42MB), and EPUB (53MB).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this book, there are more practical tutorials. In order to better understand the principles of Kubernetes, I recommend studying ** In- &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/posts/kubernetes-tutorial-recommendation/&#34; title=&#34;depth analysis of Kubernetes by Zhang Lei, produced by Geek Time&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;depth analysis of Kubernetes by Zhang Lei, produced by Geek Time&lt;/a&gt;
 **.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Kubernetes for your support of this book. Thank you &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/kubernetes-handbook/graphs/contributors&#34; title=&#34;Contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contributors&lt;/a&gt;
 . In the months before this version was released, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;ServiceMesher community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ServiceMesher community&lt;/a&gt;
 was co-founded . As a force in the &lt;strong&gt;post-Kubernetes era&lt;/strong&gt; , welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/contact&#34; title=&#34;contact me&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;
 to join the community and create &lt;strong&gt;cloud native New era&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present , the WeChat group of the &lt;strong&gt;ServiceMesher community&lt;/strong&gt; also has thousands of members. The Kubernete Handbook will continue, but Service Mesh is already a rising star. With Kubernetes in mind, welcome to join the ServiceMesher community and follow us. The public account of the community (also the one I manage).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio 1.0 is released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-v1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 14:42:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/istio-v1-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Today, we are pleased to announce &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/about/notes/1.0&#34; title=&#34;Istio 1.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio 1.0&lt;/a&gt;
 . It&amp;rsquo;s been over a year since the original 0.1 release. Since 0.1, Istio has grown rapidly with the help of a thriving community, contributors, and users. Many companies have successfully applied Istio to production today and have gained real value through the insight and control provided by Istio. We help large businesses and fast-growing startups such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebay.com/&#34; title=&#34;eBay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autotrader.co.uk/&#34; title=&#34;Auto Trader UK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Auto Trader UK&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.descarteslabs.com/&#34; title=&#34;Descartes Labs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Descartes Labs&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fitstation.com/&#34; title=&#34;HP FitStation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HP FitStation&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namely.com/&#34; title=&#34;Namely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Namely&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pubnub.com/&#34; title=&#34;PubNub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubNub&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trulia.com/&#34; title=&#34;Trulia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trulia&lt;/a&gt;
 to connect, manage and protect their services from scratch with Istio. The release of this version as 1.0 recognizes that we have built a core set of features that users can rely on for their production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year we saw a significant increase in the Istio ecosystem. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/&#34; title=&#34;Envoy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Envoy&lt;/a&gt;
 continues its impressive growth and adds many features that are critical to a production-level service grid. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datadoghq.com/&#34; title=&#34;Observability providers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Observability providers&lt;/a&gt;
 like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datadoghq.com/&#34; title=&#34;Datadog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Datadog&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.solarwinds.com/&#34; title=&#34;SolarWinds&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://sysdig.com/blog/monitor-istio/&#34; title=&#34;Sysdig&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sysdig&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/stackdriver/&#34; title=&#34;Google Stackdriver,&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Stackdriver,&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudwatch/&#34; title=&#34;Amazon CloudWatch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amazon CloudWatch&lt;/a&gt;
 have also written plugins to integrate Istio with their products. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tigera.io/resources/using-network-policy-concert-istio-2/&#34; title=&#34;Tigera&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tigera&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aporeto.com/&#34; title=&#34;Aporeto&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aporeto&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://cilium.io/&#34; title=&#34;Cilium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cilium&lt;/a&gt;
 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://styra.com/&#34; title=&#34;Styra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Styra&lt;/a&gt;
 have built extensions for our strategy implementation and network capabilities. Kiali built by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redhat.com/en&#34; title=&#34;Red Hat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt;
 provides a good user experience for grid management and observability. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudfoundry.org/&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Foundry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Foundry&lt;/a&gt;
 is building the next-generation traffic routing stack for Istio, the recently announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/docs&#34; title=&#34;Knative serverless&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Knative serverless&lt;/a&gt;
 project is doing the same, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://apigee.com/&#34; title=&#34;Apigee has&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apigee has&lt;/a&gt;
 announced plans to use it in their API management solution. These are just a few of the projects that the community added last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 0.8 release, we have added some important new features, and more importantly, marked many existing features as Beta to indicate that they can be used in production. This is covered in more detail in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/about/notes/1.0/&#34; title=&#34;release notes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;
 , but it is worth mentioning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Kubernetes clusters can now be &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/docs/setup/kubernetes/multicluster-install&#34; title=&#34;added to a single grid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;added to a single grid&lt;/a&gt;
 , enabling cross-cluster communication and consistent policy enforcement. Multi-cluster support is now Beta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The network API for fine-grained control of traffic through the grid is now Beta. Explicitly modeling ingress and egress issues with gateways allows operations personnel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/blog/2018/v1alpha3-routing/&#34; title=&#34;control the network topology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;control the network topology&lt;/a&gt;
 and meet access security requirements at the edge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two-way TLS can now be &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/docs/tasks/security/mtls-migration&#34; title=&#34;launched incrementally&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;launched incrementally&lt;/a&gt;
 without updating all clients of the service. This is a key feature that removes the barriers to deploying Istio on existing production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixer now supports &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/istio/wiki/Out-Of-Process-gRPC-Adapter-Dev-Guide&#34; title=&#34;developing out-of-process adapters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developing out-of-process adapters&lt;/a&gt;
 . This will be the default way to extend Mixer in an upcoming release, which will make it easier to build adapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Envoy now fully evaluates the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/docs/concepts/security/#%e8%ae%a4%e8%af%81&#34; title=&#34;authorization policies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;authorization policies&lt;/a&gt;
 that control service access locally , improving their performance and reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/docs/setup/kubernetes/helm-install/&#34; title=&#34;Helm chart installation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Helm chart installation&lt;/a&gt;
 is now the recommended installation method, with a wealth of customization options to configure Istio to your needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We put a lot of effort into performance, including continuous regression testing, large-scale environmental simulation, and target repair. We are very happy with the results and will share details in the coming weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-step&#34;&gt;Next step&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this is an important milestone for the project, much work remains to be done. When working with adopters, we&amp;rsquo;ve received a lot of important feedback about what to focus next. We&amp;rsquo;ve heard consistent topics about supporting hybrid clouds, installing modularity, richer network capabilities, and scalability for large-scale deployments. We have considered some feedback in the 1.0 release and we will continue to actively work on it in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are new to Istio and want to use it for deployment, we would love to hear from you. Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/docs/&#34; title=&#34;documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;
 , visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.rocket.chat/&#34; title=&#34;chat forum&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;chat forum&lt;/a&gt;
 or visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/istio-dev&#34; title=&#34;mailing list&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
 . If you want to contribute more to the project, please join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh/about/community&#34; title=&#34;community meeting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;community meeting&lt;/a&gt;
 and say hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-last&#34;&gt;At last&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Istio team is grateful to everyone who contributed to the project. Without your help, it won&amp;rsquo;t have what it is today. Last year&amp;rsquo;s achievements were amazing, and we look forward to achieving even greater achievements with our community members in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/&#34; title=&#34;The ServiceMesher community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The ServiceMesher community&lt;/a&gt;
 is responsible for the translation and maintenance of Chinese content on Istio&amp;rsquo;s official website. At present, the Chinese content is not yet synchronized with the English content. You need to manually enter the URL to switch to Chinese ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34; title=&#34;https://istio.io/zh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://istio.io/zh&lt;/a&gt;
 ). There is still a lot of work to do , Welcome everyone to join and participate.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagicSandbox Alpha released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/magicsandbox-alpha-version-annoucement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 12:35:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/magicsandbox-alpha-version-annoucement/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a visual learning model and platform that provides infrastructure clusters for your operation, would you pay for it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months ago, I met Jord in Kubernetes&amp;rsquo;s Slack channel, and later saw the link of MagicSandbox.io he (and possibly others) sent in the Facebook group of Taiwan Kubernetes User Group, and I clicked to apply for a trial Then, I received an email from Jord later, and he told me that he wanted to build a Kubernetes learning platform. That&amp;rsquo;s where the whole thing started, and then we had a couple of Zoom video chats for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-magicsandbox&#34;&gt;About MagicSandbox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MagicSandbox is a startup company. Jord (Dutch) is also a serial entrepreneur. He has studied at Sichuan University in China for 4 years since he was 19, and then returned to Germany. He worked as a PM at Boston Consulting Group and now works at Entrepreneur. First (Europe&amp;rsquo;s top venture capital / enterprise incubator) is also located in Berlin, Germany. He met Mislav (Croatian). Mislav is a full-stack engineer and has several entrepreneurial experiences. They have similar odors, and they hit it off. Decided to be committed to the Internet education industry and create a world-class software engineer education platform. They want to start with Kubernetes, first provide Internet-based Kubernetes theory and practice teaching, and then expand the topic to ElasticSearch, GraphQL, and so on. topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jord founded MagicSandbox in his home, and I became the face of MagicSandbox in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we are going to release the MagicSandbox Alpha version. This version is an immature version and is provided for everyone to try for free. Positive feedback is also welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;https://magicsandbox.com/&#34; title=&#34;https://magicsandbox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://magicsandbox.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cn.magicsandbox.com/&#34; title=&#34;https://cn.magicsandbox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cn.magicsandbox.com/&lt;/a&gt;
 (The content has not been finished yet, only the Chinese version homepage is currently provided)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow us on Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/magicsandbox&#34; title=&#34;https://twitter.com/magicsandbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/magicsandbox&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballerina seeks Chinese ambassador</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/a-ballerina-china-ambassador-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 21:23:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/a-ballerina-china-ambassador-required/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Remember the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzI1NTE2NDE2MA==&amp;amp;mid=2649381257&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=e3c3fc1ed4c9099b95fffd22ff576629&amp;amp;chksm=f224d3e6c5535af0db1b7f6c9fa85390b3e5d41f6b18d46ac8edce9304b3db2ae88c9de04bf6&amp;amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect&#34; title=&#34;cloud-native programming language&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cloud-native programming language&lt;/a&gt;
 I shared before &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzI1NTE2NDE2MA==&amp;amp;mid=2649381257&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=e3c3fc1ed4c9099b95fffd22ff576629&amp;amp;chksm=f224d3e6c5535af0db1b7f6c9fa85390b3e5d41f6b18d46ac8edce9304b3db2ae88c9de04bf6&amp;amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect&#34; title=&#34;finally appeared! &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;finally appeared! &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzI1NTE2NDE2MA==&amp;amp;mid=2649381257&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=e3c3fc1ed4c9099b95fffd22ff576629&amp;amp;chksm=f224d3e6c5535af0db1b7f6c9fa85390b3e5d41f6b18d46ac8edce9304b3db2ae88c9de04bf6&amp;amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect&#34; title=&#34;Learn about Ballerina in one article! &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learn about Ballerina in one article! &lt;/a&gt;
? They are ready to attend the KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon China Conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon China Conference will be &lt;strong&gt;held on November 14-15, 2018&lt;/strong&gt; (Wednesday, Thursday) in &lt;strong&gt;Shanghai&lt;/strong&gt; . See: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lfasiallc.com/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-china-2018/&#34; title=&#34;https://www.lfasiallc.com/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-china-2018/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.lfasiallc.com/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-china-2018/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Ballerina&amp;rsquo;s official authorization, I now need to help them find an &amp;ldquo;ambassador&amp;rdquo; in China, responsible for team guidance, Chinese and English translation, and familiarity with Cloud Native and microservices. It has influence in the industry and has no barriers to English communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambassador duties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for Chinese and English translation of product declaration, PPT materials, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help to arrange the booth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The other party can provide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference tickets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accommodation during the conference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other compensation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a photo of their team in front of their booth during the KubeCon &amp;amp; CloudNativeCon in Hagen in May this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS This is the most complete and best picture I have ever found of their team. (Photography needs to be strengthened)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly introduce this startup called Ballerina. Their team is mainly from Sri Lanka. This is an island country next to India in the South Asian subcontinent. In ancient China, it was called &amp;ldquo;Lion Country&amp;rdquo; and rich in gemstones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capital of their country is Sri Lanka, which is pronounced in their own language: Si li jia ya wa de na pu la ke te&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested, please contact me directly.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese version of the latest official document of Envoy released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/envoyproxy-docs-cn-17-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 11:50:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/envoyproxy-docs-cn-17-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Envoy-Designed for cloud-native applications, open source edge and service proxy, Istio Service Mesh default data plane, Chinese version of the latest official document, dedicated by the ServiceMesher community, welcome everyone to learn and share together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TL;DR: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF download address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/releases&#34; title=&#34;servicemesher/envoy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;servicemesher/envoy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time Community Service Mesh enthusiasts group activities, the document is based on Envoy latest (version 1.7) Official documents &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/docs/envoy/latest/&#34; title=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/docs/envoy/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.envoyproxy.io/docs/envoy/latest/&lt;/a&gt;
 . A total of 120 articles with 26 participants took 13 days and 65,148 Chinese characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit online address: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.servicemesher.com/envoy/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; : This book does not include the v1 API reference and v2 API reference sections in the official documentation. Any links to API references in the book will jump directly to the official page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributor&#34;&gt;Contributor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the contributor page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/graphs/contributors&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/graphs/contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the above contributors for their efforts! Because the level of translators is limited, there are inevitably inadequacies in the text. I also ask readers to correct them. Also welcome more friends to join our GitHub organization: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Envoy&#39;s latest official document translation work started</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/enovy-doc-translation-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 14:47:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/enovy-doc-translation-start/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://envoyproxy.io/&#34; title=&#34;Envoy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Envoy&lt;/a&gt;
 is an open source L7 proxy and communication bus written in C ++ by Lyft. It is currently an open source project under &lt;a href=&#34;https://cncf.io/&#34; title=&#34;CNCF&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt;
 . The code is hosted on GitHub. It is also the default data plane in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/&#34; title=&#34;Istio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt;
 service mesh. We found that it has very good performance, and there are also continuous open source projects based on Envoy, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/envoy/Ambassador&#34; title=&#34;Ambassador&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ambassador&lt;/a&gt;
 , &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/solo-io/gloo&#34; title=&#34;Gloo,&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gloo,&lt;/a&gt;
 etc. At present, the official documentation of Envoy has not been well finished, so we Service Service enthusiasts feel that they are launching the community The power of the co-translation of the latest (version 1.7) official documentation of Enovy and organization through GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service Mesh enthusiasts have jointly translated the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/docs/envoy/latest/&#34; title=&#34;latest version of the official document&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;latest version of the official document&lt;/a&gt;
 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/docs/envoy/latest/&#34; title=&#34;Envoy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Envoy&lt;/a&gt;
 . The translated code is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy&lt;/a&gt;
 . If you are also a Service Mesh enthusiast, you can join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher&#34; title=&#34;SerivceMesher GitHub organization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SerivceMesher GitHub organization&lt;/a&gt;
 and participate together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official Envoy document excludes all articles in the two directories of the v1 API reference and the v2 API reference. There are more than 120 documents. The length of the documents varies. The original English official documents use the RST format. I manually converted them into Markdown format and compiled using Gitbook. A GitHub Issue was generated according to the path of the document relative to the home directory. Friends who want to participate in translation can &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/about&#34; title=&#34;contact me&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;
 to join the ServiceMesher organization, and then select the article you want to translate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/issues&#34; title=&#34;Issue&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;
 , and then reply &amp;ldquo;Claim&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/servicemesher/envoy/graphs/contributors&#34; title=&#34;Here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
 you can see all the contributors. In the future, we will also create a Service Mesh enthusiast website. The website uses static pages. All code will be hosted on Github. Welcome everyone to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker container network book sharing</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/container-networking-from-docker-to-kubernetes-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 10:07:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/container-networking-from-docker-to-kubernetes-nginx/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;TL; DR &lt;a href=&#34;https://share.weiyun.com/5tGG1ya&#34; title=&#34;Click here to download the PDF of this book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to download the PDF of this book&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;em&gt;Michael Hausenblas of&lt;/em&gt; Nginx released a booklet on container networks in docker and kubernetes. This 72-page material is a good introduction for everyone to understand the network in Docker and Kubernetes from shallow to deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-audience&#34;&gt;Target audience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container Software Developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SRE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Operation and Maintenance Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architects who want to containerize traditional software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchSummit Beijing 2017 speech preview</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/archsummit-beijing-2017-from-kubernetes-to-cloud-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 12:11:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/archsummit-beijing-2017-from-kubernetes-to-cloud-native/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In 2017, we are facing a big era of architectural changes, such as Kubernetes ending the battle for container orchestration, Kafka release 1.0, serverless gradually gaining momentum, edge computing to replace cloud computing, Service Mesh ready to go, and artificial intelligence to empower business , Also brings new challenges to the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am about to participate in InfoQ&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;ArchSummit Global Architects Summit&lt;/strong&gt; on December 8-11 in Beijing . This conference also invited 100+ top technologists such as Dr. Ali &lt;strong&gt;Wangjian&lt;/strong&gt; to share and summarize the architectural changes and reflections this year. I hope that you can build on this conference, summarize past practices, and look forward to a future-oriented architecture to transform this era of change into the common fortune of each of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-speech&#34;&gt;My speech&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of my speech is &lt;strong&gt;from Kubernetes to Cloud Native-the road to cloud native applications&lt;/strong&gt; . Link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/presentation/306&#34; title=&#34;From Kubernetes to Cloud Native-the road to cloud native applications&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Kubernetes to Cloud Native-the road to cloud native applications&lt;/a&gt;
 . The time is Saturday, December 9, 9:30 am, in the fifth meeting room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After more than ten years of development of cloud computing, the new phase of cloud native has entered. Enterprise applications are preferentially deployed in cloud environments. How to adapt to the cloud native tide, use containers and Kubernetes to build cloud native platforms, and practice DevOps concepts and agility How IT, open source software, and the community can help IT transform, the solution to all these problems is the PaaS platform, which is self-evident to the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also prepared gifts for everyone: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/cloud-native-go/&#34; title=&#34;&amp;amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Go-Building Cloud Native Web Applications Based on Go and React&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud Native Go-Building Cloud Native Web Applications Based on Go and React&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
 and &amp;ldquo;Intelligent Data Era-Enterprise Big Data Strategy and Practice&amp;rdquo; There is also a book stand for the blog post of the Electronic Industry Press. Welcome to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ArchSummit conference official website link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, please refer to the official website of the conference: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://bj2017.archsummit.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudinary file upload tool written in Go released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloudinary-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 15:24:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/cloudinary-go/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloudinary-go&#34; title=&#34;Cloudinary-go&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloudinary-go&lt;/a&gt;
 is a Go client library and CLI tool to upload static assets to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudinary.com&#34; title=&#34;Cloudinary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloudinary&lt;/a&gt;
 service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the CLI tool and the library with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;go get github.com/rootsongjc/cloudinary-go/cloudinary
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or download the release binary from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/cloudinary-go/releases&#34; title=&#34;release&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Handbook is released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/building-static-website-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 22:30:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/building-static-website-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Many people asked me how jimmysong.io made this website. I think it is necessary to write a book to popularize the knowledge of static website construction and Hugo as a tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This manual will guide you how to use Hugo to build a static website for personal blog or project display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach you how to build a static website from scratch. This does not require much programming and development experience and time investment, and basically does not require much cost (except for personalized domain names). You can quickly build and Launch a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rootsongjc/hugo-handbook&lt;/a&gt;

Gitbook access address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/hugo-handbook&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/hugo-handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/hugo-handbook&lt;/a&gt;

The content of this book will continue to improve over time and as my site improves, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New domain name jimmysong.io</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/domain-name-jimmysong-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 23:48:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/domain-name-jimmysong-io/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;From now on I have my own independent domain name &lt;a href=&#34;http://jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;jimmysong.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;jimmysong.io&lt;/a&gt;
 , the website is still hosted on GitHub, the original URL &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io is&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io is&lt;/a&gt;
 still accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why use .io as the suffix? Because this is &lt;strong&gt;The First Step to Cloud Native!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why choose today? Because today is August 18, the days are easy to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS domain names are registered in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.namecheap.com/&#34; title=&#34;namecheap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;namecheap&lt;/a&gt;
 and cost tens of dollars / year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proudly powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🎉🎊🎉&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Cloud Native list is released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/awesome-cloud-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 11:21:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/awesome-cloud-native/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This is a list of software, tools, architecture and reference materials about Cloud Native. It is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/awesome-cloud-native&#34; title=&#34;awesome-cloud-native&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;awesome-cloud-native&lt;/a&gt;
 , a project I opened on GitHub , and can also be &lt;a href=&#34;http://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native&#34; title=&#34;browsed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;browsed&lt;/a&gt;
 through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native&#34; title=&#34;web page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;web page&lt;/a&gt;
 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is divided into the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awesome Cloud Native&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#ai&#34; title=&#34;AI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#api-gateway&#34; title=&#34;API gateway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;API gateway&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#big-data&#34; title=&#34;Big Data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Big Data&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#container-engine&#34; title=&#34;Container engine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Container engine&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#ci-cd&#34; title=&#34;CI-CD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CI-CD&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#database&#34; title=&#34;Database&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#data-science&#34; title=&#34;Data Science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data Science&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#fault-tolerant&#34; title=&#34;Fault tolerant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fault tolerant&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#logging&#34; title=&#34;Logging&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Logging&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#message-broker&#34; title=&#34;Message broker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Message broker&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#monitoring&#34; title=&#34;Monitoring&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#networking&#34; title=&#34;Networking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#orchestration-and-scheduler&#34; title=&#34;Orchestration and scheduler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Orchestration and scheduler&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#portability&#34; title=&#34;Portability&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Portability&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#proxy-and-load-balancer&#34; title=&#34;Proxy and load balancer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Proxy and load balancer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#rpc&#34; title=&#34;RPC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RPC&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#security-and-audit&#34; title=&#34;Security and audit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Security and audit&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#service-broker&#34; title=&#34;Service broker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Service broker&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#service-mesh&#34; title=&#34;Service mesh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Service mesh&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#service-registry-and-discovery&#34; title=&#34;Service registry and discovery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Service registry and discovery&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#serverless&#34; title=&#34;Serverless&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Serverless&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#storage&#34; title=&#34;Storage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Storage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#tracing&#34; title=&#34;Tracing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tracing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#tools&#34; title=&#34;Tools&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/awesome-cloud-native/#tutorial&#34; title=&#34;Tutorial&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list will be continuously updated and improved in the future, not only for my usual research records, but also as a reference for the Cloud Native industry.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Cloud Native Chinese version released</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/changes-needed-to-cloud-native-archtecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 15:04:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/notice/changes-needed-to-cloud-native-archtecture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This book is the Chinese version of Migrating to Cloud Native Application Architectures. The English version of this book was released in February 2015. The Chinese version was translated by Jimmy Song and published in July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub hosting address for this book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34; title=&#34;https://github.com/rootsongjc/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rootsongjc/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gitbook reading address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34; title=&#34;https://jimmysong.io/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://jimmysong.io/migrating-to-cloud-native-application-architectures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application architectures discussed in this book include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twelve-factor application: A collection of cloud-native application architecture patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservices: independently deployed services, each service does one thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-service agile infrastructure: a platform that provides application environments and back-office services quickly, repeatably, and consistently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API-based collaboration: published and versioned APIs that allow interactions between services in a cloud-native application architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure resistance: a system that becomes stronger under pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
