
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song – ICA</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/ica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ICA on Jimmy Song</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Jimmy Song</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Jimmy Song</webMaster>
    
      <follow_challenge>
        <feedId>61582075856402432</feedId>
        <userId>59800919738273792</userId>
      </follow_challenge>
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:27:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/ica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
                                                         
    
                                                   
                           
    <item>
      <title>ICA Certification: Latest Changes and Exam Preparation Guide for Istio Skills</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-certificate/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-and-reminders-for-ica-certification&#34;&gt;Changes and Reminders for ICA Certification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming policy change: Please note that the ICA certification expiration policy will change on April 1, 2024, at 00:00UTC. Certifications obtained on or after this date will expire 24 months after meeting the certification requirements (including passing the exam). We encourage anyone interested and prepared to schedule and take the exam before the policy change. Please see more detailed information &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com&#34; title=&#34;here&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current certification validity period is 3 years, and certifications obtained after April 1st will be valid for 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-on-tetrate-academy&#34;&gt;Background on Tetrate Academy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academy.tetrate.io/&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate Academy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate Academy&lt;/a&gt;, operated by Tetrate, has been around for several years, launching Istio fundamentals tutorials, Envoy fundamentals tutorials, and CIAT certification exams, with over 13,000 people having taken Tetrate Academy courses. In September last year, Tetrate contributed CIAT to CNCF, renamed it &lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;ICA exam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ICA exam&lt;/a&gt;, and the certification exam was officially launched in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;mx-auto text-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;domains.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34;
         alt=&#34;ICA domains by Linux Foundation&#34;data-img=&#34;domains.jpg&#34;
         data-caption=&#34;&#34;
         
         
         data-width=&#34;1000&#34;
         data-height=&#34;968&#34;
         
         
    /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;ICA domains by &lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;Linux Foundation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exam-background&#34;&gt;Exam Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICA is derived from the CIAT exam contributed by Tetrate, providing validation of extensive knowledge and skills in Istio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam is conducted remotely online, with a time limit of 2 hours, during which candidates need to operate Kubernetes clusters and Istio in a virtual machine environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam includes a series of problem-solving questions and some multiple-choice questions, requiring a passing score of 75%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PSI system provides an online exam environment, and exam results will be emailed to candidates within 24 hours after the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exam environment provides tools such as Kubernetes clusters, Istio installation, VS Code, kubectl, istioctl, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to Istio documentation is available during the exam, and questions and responses are in English only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations-and-reminders&#34;&gt;Recommendations and Reminders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io&#34; title=&#34;Istio documentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio documentation&lt;/a&gt; before the exam, and prepare in advance, including checking the PSI system, identification, and exam environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s free &lt;a href=&#34;https://academy.tetrate.io/courses/istio-fundamentals&#34; title=&#34;Istio fundamentals tutorial&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istio fundamentals tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to deepen your understanding of Istio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay calm during the exam, answer familiar questions first, then unfamiliar ones, to ensure efficient completion of the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-links&#34;&gt;Reference Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.linuxfoundation.org/tc-docs/certification/frequently-asked-questions-ica&#34; title=&#34;ICA Certification FAQs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ICA Certification FAQs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.linuxfoundation.org/tc-docs/certification/important-instructions-ica&#34; title=&#34;Important Instructions for ICA Certification&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Important Instructions for ICA Certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
                           
    <item>
      <title>A Month in Review: The Impact of Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification with Tetrate&#39;s Contribution</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jimmy Song</author>
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cloud computing professionals, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month since the &lt;strong&gt;Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification&lt;/strong&gt; journey began. A collaboration between the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), Linux Foundation Training &amp;amp; Certification, and Tetrate, this certification has set a new benchmark in microservices management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tetrate.io&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate&lt;/a&gt;, a key contributor to the Istio project, initially crafted the Certified Istio Administrator by Tetrate (CIAT), which laid the groundwork for the ICA Certification. Since its introduction, the ICA has been an instrumental part of the Kubernetes ecosystem, helping thousands to harness the power of service mesh technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certification curriculum covers essential domains such as &lt;strong&gt;installation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;traffic management&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;, reflecting the comprehensive expertise needed in the field. In a short span, the ICA has gained significant momentum, underpinned by the vision and dedication of Tetrate to the cloud-native landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we celebrate one month of the ICA, Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s commitment to open source education continues through their Tetrate Academy, providing free, high-quality courses on service mesh and Kubernetes security. For those aiming to deploy Istio in production, Tetrate offers the &lt;strong&gt;Tetrate Istio Distribution (TID)&lt;/strong&gt;, a secure and supported Istio distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, now is the time to join this growing community of Istio experts. Enhance your career and contribute to the evolution of cloud-native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-ica-certification-today&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning. Let&amp;rsquo;s look forward to more milestones in service mesh proficiency, with Tetrate and CNCF leading the charge.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
