<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song&#39;s blog – ICA</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/ica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ICA on Jimmy Song&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:27:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/tags/ica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Month in Review: The Impact of Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification with Tetrate&#39;s Contribution</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/blog/ica-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cloud computing professionals, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month since the &lt;strong&gt;Istio Certified Associate (ICA) Certification&lt;/strong&gt; journey began. A collaboration between the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), Linux Foundation Training &amp;amp; Certification, and Tetrate, this certification has set a new benchmark in microservices management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tetrate.io&#34; title=&#34;Tetrate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tetrate&lt;/a&gt;
, a key contributor to the Istio project, initially crafted the Certified Istio Administrator by Tetrate (CIAT), which laid the groundwork for the ICA Certification. Since its introduction, the ICA has been an instrumental part of the Kubernetes ecosystem, helping thousands to harness the power of service mesh technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certification curriculum covers essential domains such as &lt;strong&gt;installation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;traffic management&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;, reflecting the comprehensive expertise needed in the field. In a short span, the ICA has gained significant momentum, underpinned by the vision and dedication of Tetrate to the cloud-native landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we celebrate one month of the ICA, Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s commitment to open source education continues through their Tetrate Academy, providing free, high-quality courses on service mesh and Kubernetes security. For those aiming to deploy Istio in production, Tetrate offers the &lt;strong&gt;Tetrate Istio Distribution (TID)&lt;/strong&gt;, a secure and supported Istio distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, now is the time to join this growing community of Istio experts. Enhance your career and contribute to the evolution of cloud-native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-ica-certification-todayhttpstraininglinuxfoundationorgcertificationistio-certified-associate-ica&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/istio-certified-associate-ica/&#34; title=&#34;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Start Your ICA Certification Today!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning. Let&amp;rsquo;s look forward to more milestones in service mesh proficiency, with Tetrate and CNCF leading the charge.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
