<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Song - Cloud Native | Open Source | Community – 招聘</title>
    <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 招聘 on Jimmy Song - Cloud Native | Open Source | Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2020 Jimmy Song All Right Reserved;&lt;/br&gt; Powerd by Hugo with [educenter](https://github.com/themefisher/educenter-hugo) theme</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 07:28:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jimmysong.io/en/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Service Mesh company Tetrate is hiring</title>
      <link>https://jimmysong.io/en/job/tetrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 07:28:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimmysong.io/en/job/tetrate/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Join a team of world-class engineers working on the next generation of networking services using Istio, Envoy, Apache SkyWalking and a few of the open projects to define the next generation of cloud native network service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-systems-engineer-enterprise-infrastructure-data-plane-golang-or-c-developers&#34;&gt;Distributed Systems Engineer, Enterprise Infrastructure (Data plane) GoLang or C++ Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking backend software engineers experienced in building distributed systems using Golang and gRPC. We are building a secure, and highly available service mesh platform for mission-critical enterprise applications for Fortune 500 companies, spanning both the legacy and modern infrastructure. Should possess strong fundamentals in distributed systems and networking. Familiarity with technologies like Kubernetes, Istio, and Envoy, as well as open contributions would be a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;qualifications&#34;&gt;Qualifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience building distributed system platforms using C++, Golang, and gRPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Kubernetes, service mesh technologies such as Istio and Envoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent understanding of networking protocols, concepts, consistency properties of distributed systems, techniques to identify and reconcile configuration drifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience contributing to open source projects is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with the following is a plus: WebAssembly, Authorization: NGAC, RBAC, ABAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with hardware/software load balancers (F5, NGINX), HSM modules, Active Directory/LDAP is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;site-reliability-engineer-sre&#34;&gt;Site Reliability Engineer, SRE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) combines software and systems engineering to build and run scalable, massively distributed, fault-tolerant systems. As part of the team, you will be working on ensuring that Tetrate’s platform has reliability/uptime appropriate to users’ needs as well as a fast rate of improvement. Additionally, much of our engineering effort focuses on building infrastructure, improving the platform troubleshooting abilities, and eliminating toil through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;qualifications-1&#34;&gt;Qualifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematic problem-solving approach, coupled with excellent communication skills and a sense of ownership/finish and self-directed drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong fundamentals in operating, debugging, and troubleshooting distributed systems(stateful and/or stateless) and networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Kubernetes, service mesh technologies such as Istio and EnvoyAbility to debug, optimize code, and automate routine tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience programming in at least one of the following languages: C++, Rust, Python, Go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with the concepts of quantifying failure and availability in a prescriptive manner using SLOs and SLIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in performance analysis and tuning is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worldwide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are remote with presence in China, Indonesia, India, Japan, U.S., Canada, Ireland, the Netherlands, Spain, and Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send GitHub or online links that showcase your code style along with your resume to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:careers@tetrate.io&#34;&gt;careers@tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-tetrate&#34;&gt;About Tetrate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by Envoy and Istio, its ﬂagship product, Tetrate Service Bridge, enables bridging traditional and modern workloads. Customers can get consistent baked-in observability, runtime security and traffic management for all their workloads, in any environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the technology, Tetrate brings a world-class team that leads the open Envoy and Istio projects, providing best practices and playbooks that enterprises can use to modernize their people and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, pleases visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://tetrate.io&#34;&gt;tetrate.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
